<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>SGVLUG</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.sgvlug.org/</id><updated>2014-02-28T16:56:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Open Source in Education and One Laptop Per Child "2.0"</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2014/02/28/open-source-in-education-and-one-laptop-per-child-20/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-28T16:56:00-08:00</updated><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2014-02-28:2014/02/28/open-source-in-education-and-one-laptop-per-child-20/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Caryl Bigenho presents: Adventures in OSSIE-land with olpc 2.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that MIT has closed the OLPC Foundation office and the OLPC Association in
Miami has slowed production of the XO laptops, what lies in store for folks
interested in Open Source Software In Education?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adventure! Come find out how you can get involved, traveling to exotic places,
meeting interesting people, and/or developing and testing hardware and
software to continue to grow the OSSIE movement. Deployments large and small
around the globe would love to have your help. Come find out what is happening
and how you can get involved in your own OSSIE-land adventure!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Unleashing Kids and Teachers in Haiti</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2014/02/28/unleashing-kids-and-teachers-in-haiti/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-28T16:56:00-08:00</updated><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2014-02-28:2014/02/28/unleashing-kids-and-teachers-in-haiti/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Curt Thompson and James Murdza, both recently back from trips to Haiti, will
talk about the evolution of the One Laptop per Child Project into Unleash
Kids, their successes and failures working with schools, establishing a
lasting infrastructure, and the technology behind it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the projects they will talk about are a mission school using OLPC
laptops and a school server providing internet caching/filtering servers, a
remote off-the-grid school using only solar power to charge ten laptops, an
orphanage with twenty computers and miniature solar panels, and several
schools using Internet-in-a-Box, an offline source of Wikipedia, Khan Academy,
and Open Street Map.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>