<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>SGVLUG</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/feeds/posts.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.sgvlug.org/</id><updated>2017-03-09T19:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Data Carpentry and Open Science</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2017/03/09/data-carpentry-and-open-science/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-09T19:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2017-03-09:2017/03/09/data-carpentry-and-open-science/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We will be socializing until 7:30am and then we'll do our usual LUG
announcements and Linux in the News and talk about last weekend's Southern
California Linux Expo.  Presentations usually start at 8pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If we have at least 30 attendees, we will raffle off leftover booth swag.
Every attendee gets a free ticket and you will be able to buy additional
tickets at $1 apiece.  Funds raised go towards SGVTech expenses, which are
primarily Meetup fees and domain name and webhosting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The open science movement calls for open sharing of research findings and
greater trust, transparency, and reuseability in making claims and reporting
results. A researcher-to-researcher training community known as Carpentry
(Software Carpentry, Data Carpentry, and others) has emerged to prepare
researchers to practice open science using more open and collaborative
practices; open source tools; and openly licensed and distributed methods,
data, code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this program, the Head of Research Services at the Caltech Library will
describe the Carpentry movement; illustrate how lesson development and
delivery takes place; and lead participants through a sample interactive
lesson from Data Carpentry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be an interactive lesson.  Please bring a fully charged laptop.&lt;br /&gt;
Installation instructions and lesson outline will be posted ahead of time. 
OpenX has guest wifi.
&lt;strong&gt;We will comment in the Meetup, if there are any updates.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gail P. Clement
(&lt;a href="http://orcid.org/0000-0001-5494-4806"&gt;&lt;a href="http://orcid.org/0000-0001-5494-4806"&gt;http://orcid.org/0000-0001-5494-4806&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)
is a Library Administrator and science research librarian who serves as Head
of Research Services at the Caltech Library. She leads a team of subject
librarians, repository, metadata and licensing specialists who develop
knowledge management resources, publishing services, and authorship programs
for the Caltech community. In this role she also represents Caltech Library on
the Organizational Advisory Assembly for the Research Data Alliance, the
Committee on Publication Ethics, and the Overleaf Steering Committee. She is a
certified Data Carpentry Instructor, specializing in research data cleaning
and enhancement; data sharing; and citation and publication of all research
outputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Coordinator of Author Carpentry - a researcher training program in 21st
century authorship and publishing - Gail collaborates with developers and
researchers to create practical, hands-on, and useful lessons in responsible,
reproducible, and reuseable research publication. Author Carpentry builds on a
pilot lesson from Software Carpentryon Scientific Authorship. Author Carpentry
workshops are offered at Caltech and through professional groups such as the
CODATA-RDA Summer School in Research Data Science and the Association for
Artificial Intelligence 2017 Tutorial Forum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gail's professional leadership includes membership on the Research Data
Alliance-CODATA Legal Interoperability of Research Data Interest Group,
mentoring researchers from developing nations via AuthorAid; and service on
the Editorial Board for the Journal of Librarianship and Scholarly
Communication (JLSC) where she co-edited the 2015 special issue on data
sharing, data publication, and data citation. She also serves on the License
Review Committee and the Scholarly Communication Taskforce of the Statewide
California Electronic Library Consortium&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DIRECTIONS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OpenX is located in the One West Bank building @ 888 E Walnut St.  Pasadena CA, 91101. 
Entrances to the building are eastbound on Walnut, right hand side before the Lake St. 
intersection or southbound on Lake St. right hand side after the Walnut St. intersection. 
Once through the driveway, please park in the 888 Lot that has the OpenX logo displayed 
out front. Pull a ticket and bring it with you to the Meetup, we will validate your parking.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/234637699/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>SCALE, Open Mic Night</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2017/02/09/scale-open-mic-night/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-09T19:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2017-02-09:2017/02/09/scale-open-mic-night/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is no formal presentation this month.  We will have adhoc talks and discussions.  We'll also talk about SCALE 15x. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/236787668/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>SCALE, Open Mic Night</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2017/01/12/scale-open-mic-night/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-12T19:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2017-01-12:2017/01/12/scale-open-mic-night/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is no formal presentation this month.  We will have adhoc talks and
discussions including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SCALE 15x - registration, discount code, booth, SCALE A/V volunteers needed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experiments with BeagleBone Black and ESP8266 wifi chip&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(tentative) Raspberry Pi project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Survey of desired SGVLUG talks for 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/235769808/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>GitHub New Features and Webhooks and API</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2016/12/08/github-new-features-and-webhooks-and-api/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-08T19:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2016-12-08:2016/12/08/github-new-features-and-webhooks-and-api/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The wonderful folks at OpenX are hosting this meeting, and they are also providing food.  We need to provide a list 
of names to building security. RSVPs will be capped at 40.  Contact Lan if you have questions.  See end of description for OpenX map&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: Our original speaker, Christian Weber, had to cancel, but he sent us another speaker, Jennie Ohyoung, who is also a Solutions Engineer at GitHub.  The topic has changed slightly.
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Note: Our actual speaker was Michelle Unger who was gracious enough to fill in at the last minute.  Jennie Ohyoung was unable to make it due to flight cancellation.  Much thanks to Jamie Wetzel for coordinating on GitHub side.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be covering the new features that were announced at GitHub Universe as well as how GitHub and other organizations use the GitHub's webhooks and API to enhance their existing workflows within GitHub. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timetable:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7:00pm - People start to arrive and socialize&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7:15pm - SGVLUG meeting begins with announcements, Linux in the News&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7:30pm - Presentation.  (NOTE: Speaker may have to leave early.) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8:45pm - End meeting, clean up &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Directions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OpenX is located in the One West Bank building @ 888 E Walnut St.  Pasadena CA, 91101. Please note that due to construction, there 
is only one entrance for parking and the Meetup entrance has changed to be  off Walnut St.   Entrance to the parking structure 
is currently available only on Lake Ave.   Once through the driveway, please park in the 888 Lot that has the OpenX logo displayed 
out front.   (If you park in the wrong structure, we will not be able to validate.)  Pull a ticket and bring it with you to the 
Meetup, we will validate your parking.   See map below for details.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://photos3.meetupstatic.com/photos/event/c/4/8/4/600_456650308.jpeg" /&gt; 
&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/233578486/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Git Foundations: Basic Concepts and Definitions</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2016/11/10/git-foundations-basic-concepts-and-definitions/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-10T19:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2016-11-10:2016/11/10/git-foundations-basic-concepts-and-definitions/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This month, we are hosted by &lt;a href="http://www.everbridge.com/"&gt;Everbridge&lt;/a&gt; at their training center.&lt;br /&gt;
Everbridge is also sponsoring food and drink.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: The GitHub Webhooks talk with Christian Weber originally scheduled for tonight
is posponed to Dec. 8th (next LUG meetng) due to speaker illness.  We apologize for the inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mike Weilgart graciously agreed to be our last-minute substitute with his well-received
"Git Foundations: Basic Concepts and Definitions," which was presented at UUASC and LOPSA-LA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dozens of commands! Hundreds of options! Git has dumbfounded sysadmins and developers alike since its appearance in 2005. And yet, this ingenious software is among the most fantastically useful ever developed. Learn Git from the ground up and the inside out with Git Foundations Training! This talk explores Git’s internals in depth. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mike Weilgart has loved maths and computers all his life. Graduating high school at the age of 13, he thereafter worked in a variety of positions including software QA, calculus teacher, and graphic design, before resolving to put his love of computers to professional use as a Linux sysadmin and trainer. Mike currently consults at a Fortune 50 company as an automation specialist, and enjoys nothing more than training people to full mastery of their tools. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timetable:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7:00pm - People start to arrive and socialize&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7:30pm - SGVLUG meeting begins with announcements, Linux in the News, and then the presentation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9:00pm - End meeting, clean up &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Directions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The building is on Hudson Ave, between Colorado and Green St. The meeting room is off Hudson, next to the first floor gym with the classic glass walls and gym equipment.  You are responsible for your own parking.   The onsite parking is very expensive.   Please check the Parkopedia link for your options or take public transit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.parkopedia.com/parking/locations/790_east_colorado_boulevard_pasadena_ca_united_states_9q5fpzcrgvj/?arriving=201611100630&amp;amp;leaving=201611100930"&gt;http://en.parkopedia.com/parking/locations/790_east_colorado_boulevard_pasadena_ca_united_states_9q5fpzcrgvj/?arriving=201611100630&amp;amp;leaving=201611100930&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/234893164/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>3D Printing, What is it good for anyway?</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2016/10/13/3d-printing-what-is-it-good-for-anyway/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-13T19:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2016-10-13:2016/10/13/3d-printing-what-is-it-good-for-anyway/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This month, we are hosted by &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://newmatter.com"&gt;New Matter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, a new
3D printing company incubated at Idealab&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;strong&gt;  Please &lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/234113164/"&gt;RSVP on Meetup&lt;/a&gt; or email 
Lan (L dot Dang at ymail dot com). We'll head out to Du-Par's Restaurant
and Bakery (214 S Lake Ave, Pasadena) around 9:15pm for a late dinner.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave Flynn will share his extensive experience with 3D printing from the past
4 years, as well as his motivations for designing and building his own 3D
printer.  Specifically, his experience is with the RepRap style of 3D
printers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation will be short as Dave much prefers answering questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome the 3D printing community--whether they are experts or neophytes--
to share the things they've printed and spark a conversation about what we can
do with 3D printing, how to get started, and how 3D printing can be used for
art, home, hobby, and work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please contact Lan if you are bringing something for show and tell or want to do a lightning talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David M. Flynn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineer, Technician, Maker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1985 BA Industrial Arts (Metal Technology) CSULA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1987 Paper tape reader emulator, Apple //e, Pascal, 6502 assembly, Wire-
wraped I/O Card&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1991 Single spindle PCB driller w/ automatic tool change, Mac SE30+, Galil
730&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1995 Oxford V.U.E., Inc., Cupric chloride etcher controller (Vis-U-Etch 5),
TTL logic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1999 Vis-U-Etch 7, PIC16F877 based w/ ethernet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2012 First 3D printer (Bukobot 1, Deezmaker), Cable drive, Arduino Mega
based.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2012-2015 Lots-o-stuff, Tank, Nerf cannon, Robots, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2015 Designed and built a screw drive rep-rap 3D printer, Arm M3,
Smoothieware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2016 Update and upgrade of 3D printer. Beaglebone (Arm A8), Replicape,
Redeem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DIRECTIONS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idealab is located is located on Union Street near Pasadena Avenue in Old Town Pasadena.  Parking is not provided; you advised to park at one of the Pasadena city lots.  You can also check &lt;a href="http://en.parkopedia.com/parking/locations/130_w_union_st_pasadena_ca_united_states_9q5fr25t2mh/?arriving=201610131830&amp;amp;leaving=201610132130"&gt;Parkopedia&lt;/a&gt; for more detailed parking options.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idealab is host to many companies, including New Matter.  We are meeting in the large open are known as Darwin; you will be escorted by New Matter employees.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TIMETABLE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6:30pm - Setup&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7:00pm - People start to arrive and socialize  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7:30pm - SGVLUG meeting begins with announcements, Linux in the News, and then the presentation  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9:00pm - End meeting, clean up, and then head over to Du-Par's&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/234113164/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Text Processing at the Linux Command Line</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2016/09/08/text-processing-at-the-linux-command-line/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-08T19:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2016-09-08:2016/09/08/text-processing-at-the-linux-command-line/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text is everywhere but not always in a useful form.  On any given day we
encounter dozens or hundreds of data formats.  Some formats are focused on
presentation while others focus on structure at the expense of presentation.
Many times the information we need has to be found, disentangled and
manipulated before it is useful.  The easier we can navigate across these
boundaries, the more freedom we have to find new uses and insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux offers a rich array of commands and tools for text processing at the
command line.  This talk proposes a classification for different types of
command line processing tasks and then explores some of the common tools
available within each category.  Many of these tools have a host of options.
Some useful but lesser known options will be highlighted.  The tools will then
be applied to a number of examples covering data extraction, processing and
presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joel Steres spends most of his time at the command prompt.  He is still amazed
at how small specialized building blocks can be combined to achieve big
results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/233145950/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>SGVLUG/SGVHAK BBQ #4</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2016/08/20/sgvlugsgvhak-bbq-4/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2016-08-20:2016/08/20/sgvlugsgvhak-bbq-4/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You and your friends and family are invited to the SGVLUG &amp;amp; SGVHAK potluck BBQ on Saturday, August 20th from 4pm to 10pm to Lan's house in the city of San Gabriel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details about the BBQ can be found here: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/forms/sDJZPbZUTPcyQ7bA3"&gt;https://goo.gl/forms/sDJZPbZUTPcyQ7bA3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP no later than August 18th.  Some Google scripting magic automatically updates the form with how many people are expected and what people say they are bringing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon submission of RSVP, you will be directed to a confirmation page with directions to Lan's house, as well as contact info.
You can submit an updated RSVP at any time.  Lan regularly updates the spreadsheet back-end to keep things accurate and will contact you if you have questions.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>How to make the world ring for you...</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2016/08/11/how-to-make-the-world-ring-for-you/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-11T19:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2016-08-11:2016/08/11/how-to-make-the-world-ring-for-you/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do amateur radio operators, small businesses, giant corporations, E911 
systems, and Linux hobbyists all have in common?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, besides using Linux, they all are using an application called Asterisk, 
in one of its many forms, to handle telecommunications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amateur radio operators can interlink plain old telephone systems with repeaters, 
small businesses can appear to the world to be a large corporation with custom 
interactive voice response menus, and hobbyists can lower their home phone bill 
to as little as a $1.00 per month with $0.0015/minute call charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to mention to have a phone number virtually anywhere in the world termin
ate at your home,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation will introduce Asterisk, its applications, basic Python scripting, 
and many other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Paul Wilkinson holds a PhD in Computer Science from Durham University, one of 
England’s foremost, and third oldest, universities. His also holds undergraduate 
degrees in Computer Science, Mathematics, and Engineering Physics as well as a 
Master of Science in Applied Mathematics. During the course of his career, he has 
worked for a “think tank” doing mathematical modeling, then the U.S. Navy, thins 
the senior civilian, and reserve, for one of the largest police departments in 
California. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now he is a Professor of Computer Science at Pasadena City College. He holds and 
Extra Class amateur radio license and is very active within the hobby as well as 
integrating Linux and amateur radio into one cohesive unit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/232555917/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>P2P and the World of Tomorrow</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2016/07/14/p2p-and-the-world-of-tomorrow/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-14T19:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2016-07-14:2016/07/14/p2p-and-the-world-of-tomorrow/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This month, SGVLUG and InfoSec Syndicate member Ray S will give a brief
history on P2P software technology, applications and implementations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The P2P and the World of Tomorrow presentation will address a brief history on
the development on P2P software technology, applications and implementations
by the end user. Applications such as Audio Galaxy, Napster, Direct Connect,
Gnutella, Freenet, eDonkey2000, Kazaa, Morpheus, BitTorrent and Soulseek will
be discussed in the presentation. End user usage patterns based on net
cultural behavioral norms will be addressed as well as the development of
conflict as result of practicing such norms on a end user case-by-case basis.
Media attention and changes in policies of governance in relation to P2P
technology and usage are topics that will be touched on in the presentation.
New changes in P2P technology being made to maneuver difficulties that have
arisen from changes in governance policies are addressed later in the
presentation. The presentation's conclusion addresses technological
responsibility and safety practices the audience can use to prevent themselves
from becoming a marginalized end user as in the cases discussed earlier in the
presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/231506871/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Survival at C: swallowing the Red Pill</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2016/06/09/survival-at-c-swallowing-the-red-pill/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-09T19:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2016-06-09:2016/06/09/survival-at-c-swallowing-the-red-pill/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many good, experienced high-level language programmers do not learn C or C++
well until they suddenly need to write an FFI extension, make an emergency
patch to an existing C or C++ codebase, re-implement the bottleneck component
in the application stack in a fast language, take an attractive job with a
low-level programming component, or otherwise move from their comfortable
language of choice and swallow the Red Pill of coding closer to the machine.
If you are already a programmer, you don't need to be taught how to program,
and your google-fu is strong for looking up detailed syntax.  Instead, this
will be a crash course in leveraging skills you learned in a high-level
environment and transferring them to these low-level tools, acquiring some new
skills you simply never needed before, and a building a mental picture of
where the road to expert, idiomatic mastery lies.  We will focus on plain C
because C++ is too complex to cover well in a single talk, but much of the
material will apply directly to C++.  Perhaps surprisingly, some of  it will
even make you a better programmer in your favorite comfortable,  higher-level
language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some little-known facts about Dustin Laurence:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His first exposure to computers was playing Colossal Cave&lt;br /&gt;
Adventure and the bootleg Fortran IV version of Zork on his cousin's work
mainframe using a glass teletype and a modem with a cradle for the handset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His first good programming language was C.  He lies and pretends that C is where he learned to program because 8-bit BASIC is embarrassing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He once gave up trying to learn the libc low-level I/O functions from the Ultrix man pages because he thought a buffer must be some kind of abstract data type provided by the C library and he couldn't find any documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He once confidently predicted that Linux was a temporary fad that would be replaced by BSD for serious work once the Berkeley codebase was completely free.  It's probably a good thing he doesn't gamble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He avoids social media for the same reason he doesn't do crack cocaine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Directions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenX is located in the One West Bank building @ 888 E Walnut St.  Pasadena CA, 91101. Entrances to the building are eastbound on Walnut, right hand side before the Lake St. intersection or southbound on Lake St. right hand side after the Walnut St. intersection. Once through the driveway, please park in the 888 Lot that has the OpenX logo displayed out front. Pull a ticket and bring it with you to the Meetup, we will validate your parking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/229463158/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Git/GitHub, CLI Text Processing Tools, OpenSuse</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2016/05/12/gitgithub-cli-text-processing-tools-opensuse/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-12T19:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2016-05-12:2016/05/12/gitgithub-cli-text-processing-tools-opensuse/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are doing informal, short presentations this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lan will provide a basic introduction to Git and GitHub&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joel S. will do a survey of commandline text processing tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drew, our resident openSUSE guy, will also get the floor.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/229463153/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Webification (w10n) and NASA data collections</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2016/04/14/webification-w10n-and-nasa-data-collections/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-14T19:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2016-04-14:2016/04/14/webification-w10n-and-nasa-data-collections/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The wonderful folks at OpenX are hosting this meeting, and they are also providing pizza. We need to provide a list of names to building security. RSVPs will be capped at 50.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Zhangfan Xing will present webification (w10n), a data
virtualization technology that simplifies use of resources on the web
platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He will discuss science data challenges and share his experience on developing
open source solutions for NASA/JPL. In particular, he will use webification
for science (w10n-sci) as an example to demonstrate how one can bring together
a diverse set of data and visualize them, using modern web browser, in a rapid
and effective fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He will also introduce the audience to the rich data collections available at
NASA data centers and elaborate on their potential values to web data
innovators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhangfan Xing is a technical lead at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory.  For over
a decade, he has been architecting and developing Information Technology
solutions for many NASA funded mission operations and research projects. He is
specialized in search technology, data analysis, web services and their
application to mission critical information and massive scientific datasets.
His recent work on webification has lead to novel web-based applications that
have had impact on NASA's mission operations and opened doors for the creation
of advanced data access and visualization technologies. He is among the first
in realizing the potential of the Web Platform as it applies to science data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/228957857/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>A Cloud-based Architecture for Processing 3D Mars Terrain</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2016/03/10/a-cloud-based-architecture-for-processing-3d-mars-terrain/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-10T19:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2016-03-10:2016/03/10/a-cloud-based-architecture-for-processing-3d-mars-terrain/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The wonderful folks at OpenX are hosting this meeting and providing pizza and
drinks. We need to provide a list of names to building security.  We
require RSVPs by 5pm on Tuesday, March 8th.  Please keep RSVPs up-to-date,
particularly if we have a waitlist.  RSVPs will be capped at 70.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OnSight is a tool that allows scientists to work on Mars through the power of
virtual reality. The Mars terrain displayed in OnSight is produced from real
images sent back by the Curiosity rover, and rendered at 1:1 scale, as if the
user were actually standing on Mars. Behind this exciting user experience is a
powerful backend infrastructure that continually produces 3D terrain
reconstructions as new images are sent back by the Curiosity rover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The terrain build system automatically detects when new images are available,
dynamically starts and stops computing instances to handle the workload, and
presents dashboards to view the progress of terrain builds. The system runs on
Amazon's cloud services platform, using a mix of Linux and Windows virtual
computing instances. The system leverages a variety of open source projects
including NodeJS, LoopBack, Ansible, Jenkins, AngularJS, and BootStrap. In
this talk will focus on the cloud computing aspects of the terrain system,
rather than on image processing. I will present a detailed look at the parts
of this system, and discuss the team's experience adapting a desktop data
processing workflow to a cloud architecture. Please join me for an applied
look at how data processing challenges can be addressed in a cloud computing
environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parker Abercrombie is a software engineer at NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory,
where he builds software to support Mars science missions. He has a special
interest in geographic information systems, and has worked with teams at NASA
and the U.S. Department of Energy on systems for geographic visualization and
data management. Parker holds an M.A. in Geography from Boston University, and
a B.S. in Creative Studies with emphasis in Computer Science (which he swears
is more technical than it sounds) from the University of California, Santa
Barbara. In his spare time, Parker enjoys baking bread and playing the Irish
wooden flute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/228444634/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Building a Community</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2016/02/11/building-a-community/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-11T19:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2016-02-11:2016/02/11/building-a-community/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The wonderful folks at OpenX are hosting this meeting and providing pizza and
drinks. We need to provide a list of names to building security.  We
require RSVPs by 5pm on Tuesday, Feb 9th.  Please keep RSVPs up-to-date,
particularly if we have a waitlist.  RSVPs will be capped at 70.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big thanks to Bobby at OpenX for making the arrangements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz Krane started the Learn to Code LA meetup group in 2015, and with
perseverance and some luck, the community grew to over 2200 members in less
than a year. In this talk, she will share what she learned by building a
community from scratch in a field she knew nothing about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you build a community? From small open-source projects to international
movements, communities amplify our individual motivations and enable us to
create meaningful changes in the world. And on a personal level, communities
are essential for our well-being as social animals. What makes for a
successful community, and how do you persuade other people to get involved?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz Krane is the founder of Learn to Code LA, a community that introduces new
people to computer science and programming with classes and fun events.Liz is
a professional dabbler who dreams of learning something about everything.
Previously a research assistant at USC Annenberg, she currently works as a
freelance web developer, writer, photographer and designer, exploring the
intersections between technology, education and journalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At about 7:30pm, we'll start the meeting with LUG business and Linux in the
News.  The talk will start shortly afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we didn't get to raffle off much stuff at our booth at SCALE, we'll be
doing some raffles during the next few meetings.  We will draw for the raffle
before and after the talk.  You will get a raffle ticket just for showing up.
You may earn extra raffle tickets for audience participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Directions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenX is located in the One West Bank building @ 888 E Walnut St.  Pasadena CA, 91101. Entrances to the building are eastbound on Walnut, right hand side before the Lake St. intersection or southbound on Lake St. right hand side after the Walnut St. intersection. Once through the driveway, please park in the 888 Lot that has the OpenX logo displayed out front. Pull a ticket and bring it with you to the Meet-Up, we will validate your parking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/augYP-USbXc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/227991894/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>DNSSEC</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2016/01/14/dnssec/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-01-14T19:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2016-01-14:2016/01/14/dnssec/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This month, SGVLUG member Carlos Meza will preview his &lt;a href="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org/scale/14x/presentations/dnssec"&gt;SCALE 14x
talk&lt;/a&gt; on DNSSEC.
Why should you care?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"DNSSec is an absolute requirement if we want to ... use the Internet for anything non-trivial." - Cricket Liu, Leading expert on the Domain Name System (DNS)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The Internet needs this technology and it needs it now" - Vint Cerf, Father of the Internet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"It is arguably one of the most important security improvements to the Internet ever." -Steve Crocker, Internet Pioneer and Chair of the Board of ICANN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DNS (Domain Name System) is used by everyone who is a consumer of the Internet. It is a core component of the Internet, yet it is completely insecure. This puts us all at risk. DNSSEC offers a solution to address the vulnerabilities of DNS . For this reason I hope stir up demand and motivation to deploy DNSSEC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will go over the basic of DNS and its vulnerabilities. Then we will go over how DNSSEC works and the solution it provides. As users, we will look at why it is important for our safety to require that our service providers (ISPs, Registrars, Hosted Services (banking, commerce, etc)) provide DNSSEC. And we will also look at some user-end tools available to advantage of DNSSEC today.  We will go over reasons why companies would want to make the effort and investment. For sysadmins, we will go over tools to aid with deployment and some considerations  to be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its essence, DNS translates names, that humans understand, to IP addresses, that computers understand. This is how we are able to find other computers on the Internet (webpages, email servers, etc). But DNS does not provide a way to validate the answer we receive. This exposes all of us to a large vulnerability. Exploits such as DNS hijacking and DNS cache poisoning miss direct us and can lead us to potentially malicious computers. DNSSEC provides a solution to this by allowing authentication of DNS data through a chain-of- trust. Being able to trust DNS goes a long way to creating a safer Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we can trust DNS other things become possible. We can now leverage DNS to store other information such as cryptographic keys. This means we can store and trust self signed SSL certificates in DNS because it is now a trusted source. This eliminates the need for certificate authorities and the issues with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DNSSEC is a great improvement on a fundamental component of the Internet we
all us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biography:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carlos has worked many years as a system administrator. His interest include InfoSec, site reliability and automation, and open source development.  While volunteering as an Interop Team Member, he was introduced to the significance of DNSSEC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.infoworld.com/article/2608759/security/security-why-you-need-to-deploy-dnssec-now.html"&gt;Why you need to deploy DNSSec now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://pir.org/dnssec-industry-coalition-meets-with-googles-chief-internet-evangelist-vint-cerf-and-internet-
researcher-dan-kaminsky/"&gt;DNSSEC Industry Coalition Meets with Google's Chief Internet Evangelist Vint Cerf and Internet Researcher Dan Kaminsky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YHVB4MjZdZ0"&gt;2011 Steve Crocker speaks about DNSSEC Deployment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/225815816/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Year in review, SCALE, and Open Mic Night</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2015/12/10/year-in-review-scale-and-open-mic-night/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-10T19:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2015-12-10:2015/12/10/year-in-review-scale-and-open-mic-night/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is no formal presentation this month.  We will go for adhoc talks and
discussions including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SGVLUG/SGVHAK year in review  + how you can contribute to keep the group going&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Southern California Linux Expo roundtable.  What is the discount code?  Who will be speaking at SCALE?  What are the plans for our booth?  What is the SCALE A/V team working on?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jess will give an overview on the current state of Linux Desktop Environments for those curious about what else is available out there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/226415194/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Twentieth Anniversary</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2015/11/14/twentieth-anniversary/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-11-14T16:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2015-11-14:2015/11/14/twentieth-anniversary/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;SGVLUG is turning 20 and the entire Southern California Linux community is invited to share in the celebration with fun, food, and prizes! Whether you're a new or a veteran user, there's something for everyone as we reflect on what we've accomplished together and envision where we're going -- all powered by our favorite operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome former members who may have lost touch and want to reconnect with us see and some familiar faces (and some new ones too). We also would love to meet others Linux users from other groups around SoCal and hear what other groups are up to. Food and drinks will be provided, graciously sponsored by our venue host OpenX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have some great things planned for a night of fun:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community project demos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LAN gaming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux Jeopardy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSVP @ &lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/sgvlug-20th-anniversary-party-tickets-18956875525"&gt;Eventbrite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/20th_Poster.jpg"&gt; &lt;img alt="20th Anniversary Poster" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/20th_Poster_Small.jpg" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Automating Basic IT Functions with Puppet</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2015/10/08/automating-basic-it-functions-with-puppet/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-08T19:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2015-10-08:2015/10/08/automating-basic-it-functions-with-puppet/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will cover how to set up and define your home IT services from code.  Topics covered will range from installing the puppet master service, through setting up the agent service, to defining common service modules in a RedHat based environment.  Cross platform topics, including writing modules to support Windows and Ubuntu, will be covered in as much detail as interest permits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biography:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pub/matthew-campbell/13/734/495"&gt;Matt Campbell&lt;/a&gt; has been active in technology and electronics since the late 80s in a variety of roles.  His background spans technical expertise in Unix OS and kernel design, the marriage of art and technology in feature film special effects, and delivery of solutions on cloud, database, virtualized, and mobile platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt's first company was founded on principles similar to modern dev-ops practices.  Defining the data structures of DVD authoring by developing a language describing the desired layout and interaction allowed the studio to deliver products for a fraction of the cost of competitors while supporting interactivity unavailable to the major studios at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently a corporate technology strategist, he is defining services for a post cloud world with a 200,000-employee organization facing billion dollar technology budgets and rapid growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sgvlug.org/slides/151008_SGVLUG_Automation.pdf"&gt;Presentation Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/225330603/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>SGVLUG/SGVHAK BBQ #3</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2015/09/14/sgvlugsgvhak-bbq-3/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2015-09-14:2015/09/14/sgvlugsgvhak-bbq-3/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You and your family are cordially invited to the SGVLUG &amp;amp; SGVHAK potluck BBQ on Saturday, September 19th from 3:30pm to 10pm in the city of San Gabriel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP by September 17th by filling out &lt;a href="http://goo.gl/forms/5XLoeJG57k"&gt;this Google form&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will receive directions to the venue after you submit the RSVP.  You can revise your RSVP at any time. Some Google scripting magic automatically updates the RSVP with how many people are expected and what people say they are bringing. Obviously, the earlier you RSVP, the more accurately we can plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Action-Movie Crypto</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2015/09/10/action-movie-crypto/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-10T19:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2015-09-10:2015/09/10/action-movie-crypto/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This month, long-time SGVLUG member Dustin Laurence reprises his &lt;a href="https://www.socallinuxexpo.org/scale/13x/presentations/action-movie-
crypto"&gt;SCALE 13x
talk&lt;/a&gt;.   We'll also be talking about the SGVLUG BBQ for September, the 20th
anniversary party plans for November, and SCALE 14x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The details of how cryptographic algorithms are designed, implemented,
verified, and assembled into cryptosystems requires expert knowledge.
Fortunately, the big picture of how the resulting cryptosystems are used does
not. For most users and even most programmers, the underlying algorithms are
black boxes that they do not and need not understand, while the language and
conceptual framework of modern cryptography are very useful in putting those
algorithms to practical use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will sketch out that conceptual framework at action-movie speed using the
simplest of classical cryptographic algorithms to represent the modern black
boxes for concreteness while studing everything but the algorithms themselves.
After the presentation you should understand: elementary cryptographic
language, security as a probabalistic rather than absolute guarantee, why the
size of the keyspace matters, why practical security depends on choosing keys
randomly, what side-channel attacks are, what public-key cryptography is, and
what a digital signature is. You should also have the basic conceptual
framework and vocabulary for further study or self-study. The presentation
should be accessible to beginners of all ages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biography:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intending to become a programmer ("developer" hadn't been invented by the
marketing department yet), Dustin got sidetracked and spent more time than he
cares to admit doing theoretical physics, a background filled with continuous
mathematics almost entirely irrelevant to computer science and cryptography.
He eventually returned to his original love, and these days writes
cryptographic and embedded software for Gem, Inc. He believes that every
programmer and indeed every citizen must be cryptographically literate in the
world he and many, many others are busy creating. He avoids social media for
the same reason he doesn't do crack cocaine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/224577917/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Desknet: Computer Aided Math Drills for Children</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2015/08/13/desknet-computer-aided-math-drills-for-children/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-13T18:30:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2015-08-13:2015/08/13/desknet-computer-aided-math-drills-for-children/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Retired schoolteacher John "Juan" Slayton will share his cool hardware/software project, Desknet, which is aimed at allowing children to do computer-aided drills using one laptop and multiple wireless keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Behavioral Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The learner will use the Logitech wireless keyboards, observing the eccentricities resulting from the Desknet decoding strategies.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The learner will demonstrate proficiency in addition and multiplication by engaging in real-time competitive activies with his/her peers.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The learner will recognize and appropriately place his/her fingers on the home row keys, and will gain speed and accuracy in reaching for non-home- row letters.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The learner will use the Desknet system to check his/her written calculations derived from the 3rd grade math text.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The learner will create and edit coherent text, using the Desknet word processor.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The learner will anecdotally recount the development of the Desknet hardware and system code to peers as occasion demands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biography:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John  Slayton is a native of Kansas City (Missouri side), but mostly grew up in California.  He received an MA from UCLA in Linguistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early 80's he became increasingly dissatisfied with his kids' experience in the public schools and went back to school (Cal Poly Pomona)  to get a California teaching credential.  He tried to get a job with El Monte City Schools, and wound up spending the next 21 years teaching bilingual classes at LeGore School.  His class  became his lab in which he could try new things, not all of which turned out well.  But some worked.  The Desknet project is one of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/223669062/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Writing and Publishing Books with Free Software</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2015/07/09/writing-and-publishing-books-with-free-software/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-09T18:30:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2015-07-09:2015/07/09/writing-and-publishing-books-with-free-software/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The old saying goes that "everyone has a book inside of them", and advances in
technology have made publishing more accessible than ever. The opportunities
in traditional and independent publishing are wide open.  But writing a book
remains a daunting task, and new authors will encounter many steps along the
way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it take to publish information in the digital age?  Hybrid author
Nathan Haines discusses working with traditional publishers that use
proprietary software and formats, and describes the self-publishing process
from start to finish.  From ebooks to print, is Free and Open Source Software
up to the task?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biography:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nathan Haines is an author, instructor, and computer consultant who fell in
love with Ubuntu in 2005, and helped found the Ubuntu California Local
Community Team to share that excitement with others. As a current leader of
the California team and a member of the Ubuntu Local Community Council, he
works to help others support and share Ubuntu worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His mission to educate and excite people about Free Software and Ubuntu
continues with his upcoming book, Beginning Ubuntu Linux for Windows and Mac
Users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/223371319/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Docker</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2015/06/11/docker/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-11T19:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2015-06-11:2015/06/11/docker/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TOPIC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker is a hot trend in today's tech community, making it easier than ever to
containerize and deploy modern, and legacy software applications.  While often
mistaken for virtualization, containers take a new, lightweight approach to
abstracting and isolating the runtime environment, dependencies and networking
required by modern software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover how to get started with Docker, best practices for
containers and example workflows for developing and deploying containers
locally and in cloud environments. After this talk you should have the
essential building blocks for building a containerized environment and
application stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BIO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan is an IT Data Scientist in the Office of Chief Technology and Innovation
at NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory where he is using the latest software and
open hardware technology to bring new ways of working with big data and
computing infrastructure to space missions. In the past, Dan has worked for a
handful of startups and has been an avid Linux user for many years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/221830022/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Ansible</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2015/05/14/ansible/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-14T18:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2015-05-14:2015/05/14/ansible/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The wonderful folks at OpenX are hosting this meeting and providing pizza and
drinks.  &lt;strong&gt;Consequently, we require RSVPs 48 hours in advance.  RSVPs are
currently capped at 35.  We may open it up if there is demand.  Please keep
RSVPs up-to-date.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will socialize and eat around 6pm, and the talk will start at 7pm.  Big
thanks to Bobby at OpenX for making the arrangements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TOPIC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Hamilton will go over the basics of Ansible and discuss why it's a
great tool for running simple commands, complex tasks and workflows across a
group of systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ansible is a powerful but simple automation tool. Ansible is simple enough
that most developers and administrators will be able to understand the scripts
without much trouble. With this simplicity, Ansible is great for organizations
looking for a tool that both dev and ops can use together. The YAML based
syntax of Ansible is also much easier to understand than the DSL that some
other tools use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BIO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew is currently a Systems Architect at Prevoty where he focuses on
automation and infrastructure. Previously he was an SRE for Search @Twitter
and a system administrator for Eucalyptus. Andrew is passionate about cloud
computing and automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DIRECTIONS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenX is located in the One West Bank building @ 888 E Walnut St.  Pasadena CA, 91101. Entrances to the building are eastbound on Walnut, right hand side before the Lake St. intersection or southbound on Lake St. right hand side after the Walnut St. intersection. Once through the driveway, please park in the 888 Lot that has the OpenX logo displayed out front. Pull a ticket and bring it with you to the Meet-Up, we will validate your parking.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://photos3.meetupstatic.com/photos/event/9/6/4/8/600_413018472.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE ON ANSIBLE:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ansible has many features common to configuration management systems such as
Puppet and Chef. Ansible uses a simple execution model compared to Puppet and
Chef that is much easier for new users to understand. The majority of the
modules it provides are indepotent so a playbook can be run multiple times
without causing problems by running a change multiple times if it isn't
needed. The use of YAML to describe your playbooks also makes creating and
editing Ansible playbooks much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interacting directly with services such as AWS, GCE, Azure or OpenStack is
easy through a set of provided modules. Ansible allows you to create an entire
deployment framework with one tool that can provision hosts, configure and
install software, add and remove servers from a load balancer and finally
terminate the old instances. Ansible can also use dynamically generated lists
of hosts making it easy to work in highly dynamic environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most powerful features of Ansible is that hosts are accessed over
SSH. There is no need to install additional daemons or to open up additional
ports. You can simply write a playbook, give it a set of hosts to run against,
provide a set of credentials and watch Ansible do what you've told it to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also don't need to give Ansible access to root unless it is required for
the playbook. Ansible can use either sudo or su to escalate privileges for
single tasks or entire playbooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ansible core is written in Python so it's easy to run and extend. If Python is
your language of choice, Ansible provides you with a set of modules that make
writing your own modules easy. If you're not a Python developer, Ansible
allows modules to be written in any language that can accept JSON through
STDIN and then return JSON back to through STDOUT. Ansible can also be used as
a library in Python that allows you to easily take advantage of some of its
features in custom scripts. Ansible is a flexible tool that allows users to
easily perform both adhoc remote command execution and configuration
management across a group of hosts. Getting started with Ansible is easy and
has relatively low overhead. Ansible playbooks are simple enough that they can
be compared with shell scripts. We'll go over the basics of Ansible and
discuss why it's a great tool for running simple commands, complex tasks and
workflows across a group of systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/221742845/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Getting Stared With Linux: A Non-Nerd's Guide</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2015/04/09/getting-stared-with-linux-a-non-nerds-guide/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-09T19:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2015-04-09:2015/04/09/getting-stared-with-linux-a-non-nerds-guide/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dan Buthusiem will help you get an idea of what Linux is, and how to get
started with it in a totally non-committal way. Learn how to use Linux the
same way you would use your computer of choice to do non-nerd things, like
email, along with a few potentially nerdy things along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended Materials:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 laptop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 empty USB drive of at least 4 GB (8 or more preferred)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker:&lt;/strong&gt; Dan Buthusiem &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/221073539/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>OpenSCAD</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2015/03/12/openscad/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-03-12T19:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2015-03-12:2015/03/12/openscad/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;OpenSCAD is a free software program for 3D CAD modelling. Instead of an
interactive environment it uses a descriptive description language to build
objects. Dave Flynn will explain this and more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is Open SCAD?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What type of project is Open SCAD and 3D printing good for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizing the part so it will be printable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is manifold anyway?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a complex part from simple objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a demo of the process I will recreate a wheel from my Tank project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker:&lt;/strong&gt; Dave Flynn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/220661892/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Streaming-OODT: An Open-Source Platform for Big-Data Processing</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2015/02/12/streaming-oodt-an-open-source-platform-for-big-data-processing/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-02-12T19:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2015-02-12:2015/02/12/streaming-oodt-an-open-source-platform-for-big-data-processing/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Streaming-OODT was originally conceived to overcome the limitations of
traditional big-data processing and management systems. It is based on an open
source data processing framework called OODT (Object Oriented Data Technology)
and was funded by NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory's Big Data Research &amp;amp;
Technology Development initiative "Archiving, Processing and Dissemination for
the Big Data Era". The vision behind the project is to combine state-of-the-
art technologies into an easy-to-use big-data processing system prepackaged to
allow users to quickly process big-data without the need to patch together
individual technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Streaming-OODT provides both traditional batch processing as well as in-memory
MapReduce processing for use on general computing clusters. Cluster management
and multi-tenancy is provided via Apache Mesos, which manages batch processing
as well as the Streaming-OODT's underlying technologies. This ensures that
multi-tenancy is applied to both the system and the user's processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache Spark provides in-memory MapReduce processing enabling processing at
speeds hundreds of times faster than Hadoop MapReduce. This system is
augmented by Apache Kafka used to manage streaming data. This enables the user
to process streaming data alongside traditional data in Apache Spark and thus
tackle data-sets too large to persist en-masse to disk, while not losing the
ability to process data sets that already exist on disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tachyon, an in-memory distributed file system, provides lightning-fast
distributed access to data files and streams on all nodes of the cluster.
Persistence is provided by Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS) thus allowing
the user both fast data access and persistence to disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this talk is to demonstrate Streaming-OODT, which will enable
the audience to use Streaming-OODT and supporting technologies to quickly
tackle their own big-data problems. The talk will introduce Streaming-OODT,
show how to quickly install and configure the system, explain the value added
by the underlying technologies, and walk through a working example of big-data
processing. Finally, benchmarks will be presented so that the audience can see
the benefit of these technologies and their combination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker&lt;/strong&gt;: Michael Starch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/219406181/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Red Hat and Open Shift</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2015/01/08/red-hat-and-open-shift/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-01-08T19:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2015-01-08:2015/01/08/red-hat-and-open-shift/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Come to this meetup to understand more about Red Hat and OpenShift, Red Hat's
multi-language platform-of-a-service solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Red Hat:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, &lt;a href="http://redhat.com/"&gt;Red Hat&lt;/a&gt; has grown from a single Linux distribution to a 20 year old, 1.5+ billion USD company with a portfolio of products in Operating System, Virtualization, Storage, Middleware and Cloud. We'll do a general overview of the company and talk about where the company is going to in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Red Hat OpenShift:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openshift.com/"&gt;OpenShift&lt;/a&gt; is Red Hat's award winning, #1  leader on Gartner's Magic Quadrant Platform-as-a-Service (PaaS) that allows developers to quickly develop, host, and scale applications in a cloud environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://linkedin.com/in/atwong"&gt;Albert T. Wong&lt;/a&gt; is a solution architect at Red Hat.  Jack of all trades in JavaEE, Red Hat and IBM Software and open source. Has a deep background in eCommerce and building, deploying and scaling very large websites. Albert is a UC Irvine Information and Computer Science alum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/218696335/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Presentation Material: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sgvlug.org/slides/About_Red_Hat-Presentation.pdf"&gt;About Red Hat&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://prezi.com/iowwgk9w_srj/introduction-to-openshift/"&gt;Introduction to OpenShift&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.sgvlug.org/slides/Introduction_to_OpenShift.pdf"&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>AROS Research Operating System</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2014/12/11/aros-research-operating-system/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-12-11T19:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2014-12-11:2014/12/11/aros-research-operating-system/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;AROS is an open source re-implementation of Amiga OS 3.1. This year with the Directory Opus 5 bounty, the ABI V1 on-trunk merge and the release of Icaros v2, that will be covered, it has been a very significant year for the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simone Bernacchia is a web developer with a background as graphic artist and musician on a couple of Amiga games. He also has a blog where he writes about retro Amiga games, protracker music composing and AROS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker:&lt;/strong&gt; Simone Bernacchia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/218696476/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Presentation Material: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.sgvlug.org/slides/icaros_presentation_20141211.pdf"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Amateur High Altitude Ballooning</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2014/10/29/amateur-high-altitude-ballooning/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-29T21:31:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2014-10-29:2014/10/29/amateur-high-altitude-ballooning/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover the stories and engineering challenges faced by the Null
Space Labs High Altitude Ballooning team and how they designed, analyzed, and
flew hardware and software to survive the harsh conditions of near space.
Recent flights include CUBEX, a payload capable of live image transmission,
solar changing, power management, and position reporting, as well as the
HABEXpico flight which flew half way across the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenter&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="http://arkorobotics.com/"&gt;Arko&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/215497372/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Meetup Event Page" src="http://www.sgvlug.org/images/meetup_logo_45.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links mentioned in the talk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://habexproject.org/"&gt;HABEX1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wiki.032.la/habex2"&gt;HABEX2&lt;/a&gt; (includes links to calculators, instructions, math, details, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/arkorobotics/sets/72157637213955175/"&gt;HABEXpico2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://hackaday.io/project/270-cubex"&gt;CUBEX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/arkorobotics/sets/72157633237341531/"&gt;HABEX2 Flight Pictures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/arkorobotics/"&gt;Arko's Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://arkorobotics.com/"&gt;Arko's Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://pi-in-the-sky.com/"&gt;Excellent RPI shield for HABs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.habduino.org/"&gt;Excellent Arduino shield for HABs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=4-v-B03a1Jk"&gt;Detailed talk on building your own HAB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://arkorobotics.com/blog/?p=113"&gt;Talk about building your own environmental chamber&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://arkorobotics.com/blog/?p=113"&gt;Blog about the environmental chamber&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wiki.ukhas.org.uk/"&gt;Best wiki for high altitude ballooning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Git and GitHub Tips and Tricks</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2014/10/08/git-and-github-tips-and-tricks/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-08T11:30:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2014-10-08:2014/10/08/git-and-github-tips-and-tricks/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Git is a popular distributed version control system, and GitHub is a platform
for Git users to share their code and projects with others, among other
things.  Lan will share tips and tricks for Git and GitHub that will be useful
to users of all levels.  Feel free to come and share your own tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenter:&lt;/strong&gt; Lan Dang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/SGVTech/events/208382952/"&gt;Meetup Event Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>PostgreSQL Authentication Mechanisms.</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2014/09/05/postgresql-authentication-mechanisms/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-09-05T21:38:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2014-09-05:2014/09/05/postgresql-authentication-mechanisms/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;PostgreSQL is the only open source database that supports identifying users
with either of the non-password standards, and the ability to do it on both
Windows and Unix platforms. Henry Hotz will illustrate how to make use of
each, and discuss the security implications of using better authentication
mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenter:&lt;/strong&gt; Henry Hotz&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Building Droplabs: A Business Model for the Open Source Community</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2014/08/11/building-droplabs-a-business-model-for-the-open-source-community/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-08-11T12:48:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2014-08-11:2014/08/11/building-droplabs-a-business-model-for-the-open-source-community/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Christefano Reyes and Lee Vodra will present: &lt;strong&gt;Building Droplabs: A Business
Model for the Open Source Community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2011, Droplabs is a coworking space, classroom and makerspace in
Downtown Los Angeles. Our community is made up of members who support each
other personally and professionally in a positive environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coworking services and developer programs we offer, like Free Coworking
Days, Coders with a Cause, Mobile Device Lab and Developer Boot Camps, were
made possible because of our love of open source and a passion for learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd love to see more places like Droplabs, and we're happy to talk at SGVLUG
about how others can replicate our success - and avoid or overcome the
challenges we've had over the years:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifying a space to build a location-based community  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traffic and parking in Downtown Los Angeles  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making decisions in a consensus-based organization  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empowering members to become leaders  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disrupting the coworking business model  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paying the bills (rent, insurance, staff, etc.)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;... and still having fun!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Raspberry Pi Retro Camera</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2014/07/09/raspberry-pi-retro-camera/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-09T12:48:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2014-07-09:2014/07/09/raspberry-pi-retro-camera/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;James McDuffie gave a presentation on his Raspberry Pi Camera project. He has hollowed out a film camera and put in a Raspberry Pi, camera, and some other electronics to make a retro-looking camera that actually takes digital photos -and- allows ssh access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had close-up pictures of the electronic components and detailed explanations of why he chose a particular component, why he modified it, and how it fit into the project. James' particular focus was on energy efficiency, so he went through a lot of trouble to modify the board to use 3.3v power from a cellphone battery.  He also looked for low-power components and ways to save power.  Because there is no leds or lcd, he used beeps to provide feedback from the camera during operation.  He also has a six-position knob that allows him to do things like turn on the system, turn off the camera portion, or to send the halt command to the Raspberry Pi.  There is room for more features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has set up a webserver on the Raspberry Pi using nginx and Flask.  This allows access to the photos on the Pi.  Aside from a serial connection and the controls from the camera, the only way to "talk" to the Raspberry Pi is through the webserver or ssh.  The Raspberry Pi is set up to automatically connect to known networks in the wpa supplicants file.  The actual camera operation is handled through a Python library called &lt;a href="http://picamera.readthedocs.org/en/release-1.5/"&gt;picamera&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Data Roads, Data Flow Centric Networks, and DaFODeL</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2014/06/04/data-roads-data-flow-centric-networks-and-dafodel/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-04T22:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2014-06-04:2014/06/04/data-roads-data-flow-centric-networks-and-dafodel/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After over 12 years trying to get the video games studio industry to both
create and use more open source software and unrestricted hardware, Jared
Hardy finally gave up on those proprietary-minded fools, and started building
NELA-ISC.Net instead. In the process of bootstrapping this Northeast LA
community utility cooperative (still in progress), he discovered the catch-22
of funding nonprofit community projects that can never take any tax deductible
donations or returns-based investments. He then started the deductible-
donation accepting Data Roads Foundation to help solve that catch-22
investment problem -- among other issues inherent to all cooperatively owned
networks. More about that and his other yak shaving projects are available in
the links below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://DataRoads.org/"&gt;Data Roads Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://NELA-ISC.Net/"&gt;North East Los Angeles Infrastructure Service Cooperative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://Unwatch.Me/"&gt;Unwatch.Me! Your personal privacy cloud.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://igg.me/at/Unicorns-and-Gigabits-LA/"&gt;Unicorns, Gigabits, and free WiFi for the City of Angels!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/10SpOWcKH0IbjZkwJbMB2l4hcZm-lH2tlOi7qimz__-w/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;Presentation from SCALE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the content in these links create more questions than answers, that will
provide good conversation fodder for Thursday night 6/12!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>SGVLUG/SGVHAK BBQ #2</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2014/05/13/sgvlugsgvhak-bbq-2/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-05-13T20:44:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2014-05-13:2014/05/13/sgvlugsgvhak-bbq-2/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You and your family are cordially invited to the SGVLUG &amp;amp; SGVHAK potluck BBQ on Saturday, May 17th from 11am to 6pm in the city of San Gabriel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP by May 15th by filling out this Google form: &lt;a href="http://bit.ly/QpLJeP"&gt;http://bit.ly/QpLJeP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will receive directions to the venue after you submit the RSVP.  You can revise your RSVP at any time. Some Google scripting magic automatically updates the RSVP with how many people are expected and what people say they are bringing. Obviously, the earlier you RSVP, the more accurately we can plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Show Off Your Projects</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2014/05/05/show-off-your-projects/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-05-05T14:27:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2014-05-05:2014/05/05/show-off-your-projects/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This month we will have a focused sort of open mic night. We will be featuring
a sort of show and tell for projects. If you have been working on something in
your spare time then we can find time for you to tell us about it. Bring
hardware, pictures or slides, whatever you need to let us know the cool things
you are doing. After getting our dinner orders in we will informally invite
people to share.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Open Source in Education and One Laptop Per Child "2.0"</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2014/02/28/open-source-in-education-and-one-laptop-per-child-20/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-02-28T16:56:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2014-02-28:2014/02/28/open-source-in-education-and-one-laptop-per-child-20/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Caryl Bigenho presents: Adventures in OSSIE-land with olpc 2.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that MIT has closed the OLPC Foundation office and the OLPC Association in
Miami has slowed production of the XO laptops, what lies in store for folks
interested in Open Source Software In Education?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adventure! Come find out how you can get involved, traveling to exotic places,
meeting interesting people, and/or developing and testing hardware and
software to continue to grow the OSSIE movement. Deployments large and small
around the globe would love to have your help. Come find out what is happening
and how you can get involved in your own OSSIE-land adventure!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Unleashing Kids and Teachers in Haiti</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2014/02/28/unleashing-kids-and-teachers-in-haiti/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-02-28T16:56:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2014-02-28:2014/02/28/unleashing-kids-and-teachers-in-haiti/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Curt Thompson and James Murdza, both recently back from trips to Haiti, will
talk about the evolution of the One Laptop per Child Project into Unleash
Kids, their successes and failures working with schools, establishing a
lasting infrastructure, and the technology behind it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the projects they will talk about are a mission school using OLPC
laptops and a school server providing internet caching/filtering servers, a
remote off-the-grid school using only solar power to charge ten laptops, an
orphanage with twenty computers and miniature solar panels, and several
schools using Internet-in-a-Box, an offline source of Wikipedia, Khan Academy,
and Open Street Map.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Lightning Talks</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2014/01/13/lightning-talks/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-01-13T22:33:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2014-01-13:2014/01/13/lightning-talks/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We will cover group business at the beginning then go through a series of
quick talks. These talks will be 2-5 minute long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard will report status on social media effort&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James will demonstrate how to update the SGVLUG website using Pelican and
Github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jess will talk about GStreamer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John K. will present the history of open source&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Reorganizing Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2014/01/06/reorganizing-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-01-06T10:03:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2014-01-06:2014/01/06/reorganizing-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;font color="red"&gt;NOTE: We are no longer meeting at Caltech.  Please check each meeting notice to see where we will be meeting.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month we are meeting at Burger Continental, not just for dinner but for the whole meeting.  We will be in the back room that is on your left just as you walk in from the back parking lot. The meeting will be focused on organizing future meetings and group business. The topics for discussion are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meeting room options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upcoming meetings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ways to promote: Meetup.com, Facebook, Twitter, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SCaLE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Github Enterprise for JPL</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2013/11/27/github-enterprise-for-jpl/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-11-27T08:48:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2013-11-27:2013/11/27/github-enterprise-for-jpl/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;GitHub Enterprise for JPL is a new collaboration center that aims to improve the state of software development by promoting collaboration between software developers. Come hear the story behind how this new service came into being and how state-of-the-art software development tools are being promoted on the grounds of the Jet Propulsion Laboratory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bio: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Mittman is Deputy Manager for Planning and Execution Systems at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory, where he leads the development of the Section’s portfolio of software for planning and monitoring the execution of activities on JPL’s robotic spacecraft. David has developed software and operated space flight missions for over 25 years and has recently started concentrating on modernizing the state of software development at JPL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brett George is a Software Engineer in the Data Services group at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory.  Brett got his start writing instrument control and data acquisition software for neutron spectrometers at the National Institute of Standards and Technology.  Since coming to JPL, he has been part of a core group of engineers leading the research and development of cloud technology to empower missions across the lab and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Witoff is the IT Data Scientist at the NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory and a Y Combinator startup founder.  His background includes development lead for interplanetary data visualization software and space station systems lead for the experimental OPALS laser communication satellite.  Rob is NASA’s first IT Data Scientist and his data science team is incubating solutions to Big Data problems for spacebound explorers, earthborn assets and the people that make them possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker:&lt;/strong&gt; David Mittman, Bret George, Robert Witoff &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Thursday December 12, 2013 @ 7pm &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Caltech - Downs 107. &lt;br/&gt;
The Downs building is across from the tennis courts on California at Arden&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>SGVLUG/SGVHAK BBQ #1</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2013/11/16/sgvlugsgvhak-bbq-1/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-11-16T19:32:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2013-11-16:2013/11/16/sgvlugsgvhak-bbq-1/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You and your family are cordially invited to the SGVLUG &amp;amp; SGVHAK potluck BBQ this Saturday, November 16th, from 1-6pm.  It will be in San Gabriel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a joint effort:
+ Steven Doran is bringing bratwurts and beer.
+ Michael Starch will be in charge of grilling.
+ Lan will be providing the venue and organizing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP using the Google form: &lt;a href="http://bit.ly/17oDrvK"&gt;http://bit.ly/17oDrvK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will receive directions to the venue after you submit the RSVP.  You can revise your RSVP at any time.  Some Google scripting magic automatically updates the RSVP with how many people are expected and what people say they are bringing.
Obviously, the earlier you RSVP, the more accurately Lan can plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>BIG DATA! 24 hour near real time processing and computation for the JPL Airborne Snow Observatory</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2013/10/21/big-data-24-hour-near-real-time-processing-and-computation-for-the-jpl-airborne-snow-observatory/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-21T06:24:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2013-10-21:2013/10/21/big-data-24-hour-near-real-time-processing-and-computation-for-the-jpl-airborne-snow-observatory/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;JPL's Airborne Snow Observatory is an integrated imaging spectrometer and scanning LIDAR for measuring mountain snow albedo, snow depth/snow water equivalent, and ice height (once exposed), led by PI Dr. Tom Painter.  The team recently wrapped our "Snow On" campaign where over a course of 3 months, we flew the Tuolumne River Basin, Sierra Nevada, California above the O'Shaughnessy Dam of the Hetch Hetchy reservoir; focusing initial on the Tuolumne, and then moving to weekly flights over the Uncompahgre Basin, Colorado.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To meet the needs of its customers including Water Resource managers who are keenly interested in Snow melt, the ASO team had to develop and end to end 24 hour latency capability for processing spectrometer and LIDAR data from Level 0 to Level 4 ("ish") products. Fondly referring to these processing campaigns as "rodeos" the team rapidly constructed an open source data processing system at minimal cost and risk that not only met our processing demands, but taught the entire team many lessons about remote sensing of snow and dust properties, algorithm integration, the relationship between computer scientists, and snow hydrologist; flight and engineering teams, geographers, and most importantly lessons about camaraderie that will engender highly innovative and rapid data systems development, and quality science products for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Mattmann is the Compute Lead for the ASO project and he will humbly tell the story of the Compute processing capability on behalf of the larger team, highlighting contributions of its key members along the way&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker:&lt;/strong&gt; Chris Mattman &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Thursday November 14th, 2013 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Caltech - Downs 107. &lt;br/&gt;
The Downs building is across from the tennis  courts on California at Arden. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Using Open-Source Tools for HW/SW Development at JPL</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2013/10/03/using-open-source-tools-for-hwsw-development-at-jpl/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-03T10:56:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2013-10-03:2013/10/03/using-open-source-tools-for-hwsw-development-at-jpl/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;font color="red"&gt;Please note that the previously advertised presentation "BIG DATA! 24 hour near real time processing and computation for the JPL Airborne Snow Observatory" is being rescheduled for another time.   Big thanks to Dmitriy and Tom for being willing to put together a presentation for us on short notice.   Cookies have been promised.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom and Dmitriy will present on how they use open source tools at JPL in their line of work.
These tools include: Raspi, GStreamer, Mercurial/Trac, Wireshark, vi, and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIO:
Dmitriy Bekker and Thomas Werne are currently staff engineers in the Instrument Flight and GSE Software group in the Instrument Electronics and Sensors Section at JPL. They are working on FPGA-based data acquisition and processing designs for multiple prototype science instruments for ground, space, and airborne applications as well as technology development for small satellites. Their projects have been deployed to the Mojave Desert, on high altitude aircraft, at observatories, and on CubeSats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker:&lt;/strong&gt; Dmitriy Bekker and Thomas Werne &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Thursday October 10th, 2013 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Caltech - Downs 107. &lt;br/&gt;
The Downs building is across from the tennis  courts on California at Arden. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Introduction to Security using Raspberry Pis</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2013/09/10/introduction-to-security-using-raspberry-pis/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-10T15:49:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2013-09-10:2013/09/10/introduction-to-security-using-raspberry-pis/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We will demonstrate 4 basic security topics, all using the Rasberry Pi computer.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topcs include: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Change Default Passwords, or Else.....if"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Clear Text Passwords and HTTP Make Jack a Sad Boy"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Cookie Stealing with Joe Blackhat"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Stack Smashing in the Real World".  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come to learn a taste of security, or simply enjoy the show.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(You can also come for the cookies and/or pie, which was what the presenters demanded as a bribe.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Michael Starch and Steven Doran &lt;br/&gt;
Date: Thursday, September 12th, 2013 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
Location: Caltech - Downs 107&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE&lt;/em&gt;: For those of you who skip the meeting but come to dinner, please be aware that Burger Continental has been shut down by the health department.  Even if it were to reopen in time, there have been some rumblings about picking another post-LUG dinner place.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Open Mic/Mike Night</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2013/08/08/open-micmike-night/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-08-08T02:02:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2013-08-08:2013/08/08/open-micmike-night/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We will have short presentations/discussions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defcon highlights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practical awk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steelbolt Hacking &amp;amp; Demo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Junaid for reserving Downs 107.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker&lt;/strong&gt;: SGVLUG &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: Thursday, August 8, 2013 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: Caltech - Downs 107 &lt;br/&gt;
The Downs building is across from the tennis courts on California at Arden. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Distributed Version Control &amp; Mercurial</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2013/07/09/distributed-version-control-mercurial/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-09T12:37:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2013-07-09:2013/07/09/distributed-version-control-mercurial/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lan will talk about distributed version control systems (DVCS) with a focus on Mercurial. The talk will be suitable for both beginners and advanced users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She will go over the basic concept behind DVCS, such as directed acyclic graphs. She will highlight some of the differences between Mercurial and git, the other popular DVCS. For the beginners, she will go over some basic Mercurial commands. For the advanced users, she will share some interesting case studies from work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker&lt;/strong&gt;: Lan Dang &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: Thursday, June 13th, 2013 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: Caltech - Downs 107 &lt;br/&gt;
The Downs building is across from the tennis courts on California at Arden. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Mini Discussions, Python for Scientific Computing</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2013/06/12/mini-discussions-python-for-scientific-computing/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-06-12T12:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2013-06-12:2013/06/12/mini-discussions-python-for-scientific-computing/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We will have a few mini presentations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redirecting stdout and stderr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using vim registers and visual selection for copy and pasting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also if time permits there will be a presentation on Python for Scientfic Computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: Thursday, June 13th, 2013 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: Caltech - Downs 107 &lt;br/&gt;
The Downs building is across from the tennis courts on California at Arden. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Redmine</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2013/04/29/redmine/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-04-29T12:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2013-04-29:2013/04/29/redmine/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Christefano Reyes presents on Redmine, a free and open source project
management and issue tracking system written in Ruby on Rails. Prior to
this presentation, attendees are welcome and encouraged to 
&lt;a href="http://www.redmine.org"&gt;download it&lt;/a&gt;, use a 
&lt;a href="http://demo.redmine.org"&gt;shared demo&lt;/a&gt;
or try a private, &lt;a href="http://www.webenabled.com"&gt;one-click install&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Popular with (but certainly not limited to) the Ruby on Rails developer
community, Redmine is a full-featured system used by companies, open
source projects, governmental agencies, and individual developers around
the world. Big users of Redmine include open source projects such as
Ruby, Puppet, Gentoo, Lighttpd, TYPO3, and the Redmine project itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation will focus on how Redmine is used from the
perspectives of developers, tech leads and project managers at a
software development company. Features that will be demonstrated include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User and group management;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feeds, email notifications and web-to-mail and mail-to-web support;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Per-project role-based permissions,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time tracking and reports; including calendaring and Gantt charts;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Issue workflow management across multiple roles;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redmine's plug-in architecture and growing developer ecosystem;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom fields for extending user accounts, time entries, and other
data structures;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redmine's REST API and how it integrates with third-party platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christefano is one of the founders of Exaltation of Larks, a Drupal
strategy, development and training company; and Droplabs, a coworking
space and classroom near Downtown Los Angeles. As an advocate of open
source software, he helps organize meetups and conferences all over the
Greater Los Angeles Area. In his spare time, he trains as an amateur
acrobat and gymnast at the Original Muscle Beach in Santa Monica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker:&lt;/strong&gt; Christefano Reyes &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Thursday May 9th, 2013 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Caltech - Downs 107. &lt;br/&gt;
The Downs building is across from the tennis  courts on California at Arden. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>The Internet-in-a-Box Project</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2013/03/27/the-internet-in-a-box-project/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-27T14:56:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2013-03-27:2013/03/27/the-internet-in-a-box-project/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are building the Internet-in-a-Box - A small, inexpensive device which
provides essential Internet resources without any Internet connection.  It
provides a local copy of half a terabyte of the world's Free information.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The device includes Wikipedia in a dozen languages, a library of 40,000
e-books, most of the world's open source software and source code, hundreds of
hours of instructional videos, and world-wide mapping down to street level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can deploy a "knowledge hotspot" anywhere in the world - even under solar
power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Open Source project is being developed by SGVLUG and SGVHAK
members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker:&lt;/strong&gt; Braddock Gaskill (braddock .at. braddock.com) &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Thursday April 11th, 2013 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Caltech - Downs 107. &lt;br/&gt;
The Downs building is across from the tennis  courts on California at Arden. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Wireless Security and DD-WRT</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2013/03/12/wireless-security-and-dd-wrt/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-12T23:02:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2013-03-12:2013/03/12/wireless-security-and-dd-wrt/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Steven Doran will discuss network router and wireless security, including replacing the stock routers  firware with an open source alternative called DD-WRT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker:&lt;/strong&gt; Steven Doran &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Thursday March 14th, 2013 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Caltech - Downs 107. &lt;br/&gt;
The Downs building is across from the tennis  courts on California at Arden. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Vim Tips and Tricks: A Roundtable Discussion</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2013/02/09/vim-tips-and-tricks-a-roundtable-discussion/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-09T21:12:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2013-02-09:2013/02/09/vim-tips-and-tricks-a-roundtable-discussion/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lan Dang will demonstrate some of her favorite tricks for the Vim text editor as well as useful vi key bindings. She welcomes everyone to contribute their own tips.  At the end, we hope to gather our tips and use cases into a document, which will be linked through the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you use Vim as seldom as possible or you use it every day, you will learn something from this session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt;: The Vim Roundtable presentation (with updates and notes) can be found &lt;a href="http://bit.ly/WLQ50F"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker:&lt;/strong&gt; Lan Dang + SGVLUG &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Thursday February 14th, 2013 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Caltech - Downs 107. &lt;br/&gt;
The Downs building is across from the tennis  courts on California at Arden. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio:&lt;/strong&gt; Lan Dang spends the majority of her working hours monitoring and troubleshooting data processing systems on Linux-based computer clusters.  She has accumulated a number of tips and tricks to deal with the command line, including extensive use of vim and vi key bindings.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Proxies and Tunnels to Freedom</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2013/01/08/proxies-and-tunnels-to-freedom/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-01-08T07:38:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2013-01-08:2013/01/08/proxies-and-tunnels-to-freedom/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since the dawn of the internet, men have tried to restrict the freedoms of other men. Amongst those bound by the restrictions of the technocracy, enlightened individuals created technologies to sidestep the restrictions placed upon them. These technologies, although effective, remain cryptic to the bound masses of the technologically illiterate.  What follow is a brief introduction to ssh tunnels and proxies...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bio:  Michael Starch was born in the far-frozen Northlands of the American Midwest.  After being enlighten through a university education in Computer Engineering he set sail for the warm coasts of the Californian Southland.  He is currently employed and has yet to die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Michael Starch &lt;br/&gt;
Date: Thursday, January 10th, 2013 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
Location: Caltech - Downs 107&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: There will be a brief presentation before the talk where Lan Dang will share her experiences rooting the Nook Simple Touch.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Rebuilding an Enterprise Class Linux Infrastructure in Under an Hour</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2012/12/03/rebuilding-an-enterprise-class-linux-infrastructure-in-under-an-hour/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-12-03T10:16:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2012-12-03:2012/12/03/rebuilding-an-enterprise-class-linux-infrastructure-in-under-an-hour/</id><summary type="html">&lt;iframe width="960" height="720" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/WwtgfQJ0MzI" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/slides/201212_David_Rodriguez_on_Chef.pdf"&gt;Slides in PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note that we are in a different room this month. Signs will be posted, but please check out the directions given under Location:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A modern day Linux Infrastructure should be flexible, scalable and able to deal
with the constant changes any business will require.  Automation is key to a
reliable and consistence server infrastructure, Automation also allows for easy
integration of new changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DevOps movement melds two traditionally siloed teams; Application
Developers and Operations Engineers.  Writing infrastructure as code presents a
number of challenges and potential pitfalls, Operations Engineers need to write
code (something they may not be familar with) and Developers need to have a
strong understanding of the system (many Developers don't want to be considered
with anything other than web applications).  There are several major projects
related purely to the management of infrastructure as code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will examine Opscode Chef and make a strong use case for the implementation
of Opscode Chef in a Linux Environment.  David will demonstrate many techniques
to utilize Chef quickly and efficiently to minimize the time of implementation.
Although Opscode Chef can be run on Solaris, FreeBSD and even Windows, the
presentation will discuss Linux and only Linux.  David will also discuss the
techniques to operate Chef on various Linux Distros which can provide a layer
of abstraction from the package management systems (apt &amp;amp; yum).  Finally David
will discuss how Chef can be used to rebuild an Entire infrastructure
(regardless of size or complexity) in a time previous thought impossible.  The
only limitation in speed of deployment is the hardware.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker:  David Rodriguez &lt;br/&gt; 
Date: Thursday, December 13th, 2012 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
Location: Caltech - Lauritsen 269.  Lauritsen is connected to Downs; the room is a lecture hall on the 2nd floor towards northeast end. The buildings are located across from the tennis courts on California at Arden. If you enter near our usual room (Downs 107),  go down the hallway, hang a right, go past the elevators, and take the stairs up one level.  As soon as you come out on the 2nd floor, the classroom is on the left hand side.  If you take the elevator, you will want to head left after getting off the elevator.  (There is a map taped next to elevator on the 2nd floor that shows the layout of Lauritsen.) &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Open Discussion November 2012</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2012/11/05/open-discussion-november-2012/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-11-05T18:36:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2012-11-05:2012/11/05/open-discussion-november-2012/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is no scheduled speaker. We will have open discussion, continued afterwards at Burger Continental.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note that we are in a different room this month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: You! &lt;br/&gt; 
Date: Thursday, November 8, 2012 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
Location: Caltech - Downs 119&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>strace: Practical Application Troubleshooting...</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2012/10/11/strace-practical-application-troubleshooting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2012-10-11:2012/10/11/strace-practical-application-troubleshooting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;strace: Practical Application Troubleshooting...&lt;br /&gt;
using the tool we all love to hate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Presentation will cover the Linux command line utility 'strace' and some of it's many uses.  It will cover the basics of Linux System Calls and their use.  The presentation will use examples throughout to provide genuine use-cases for the tool.  The Presentation is focused on Practical Application Troubleshooting, it will not be an in-depth guide to the various System Calls.  I will demonstrate many techniques that can help you to gain a deeper understanding of application execution flow on a Linux system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: David Rodriguez  --  otherwise known as... ‘D Rod’ &lt;br /&gt;
  Currently working as Linux Systems Engineer -- managing various types of Linux servers (Web App, DB, Chef, Nagios, etc.)&lt;br /&gt;
  3+ years as a Linux Systems Engineer&lt;br /&gt;
  5+ years as a Windows Systems Engineer&lt;br /&gt;
  10+ years as a Linux User&lt;br /&gt;
  B.S. in Information Systems Security &amp;amp; A.S. in Computer and Electronic Engineering&lt;br /&gt;
  Strong Advocate for Open Source&lt;br /&gt;
  I like to break web applications...   :-)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday, October 11, 2012 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
Location: Caltech - Downs 107&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>SGVHAK SIG Kickoff</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2012/09/20/sgvhak-sig-kickoff/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2012-09-20:2012/09/20/sgvhak-sig-kickoff/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are interested in the group, please sign up for the [SGVHAK mailing list] (http://sgvlug.org/mailman/listinfo/hak "SGVHAK Mailing List Sign Up").  We will continue to crosspost announcements to the SGVLUG mailing list. We are in the process of setting up a website or subpage.&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you like working on hardware projects?  Did you just get a Raspberry Pi/Arduino/Kinect with the intentions of doing something cool?  Did you wish that there was a local meetup group where you can meet up with like-minded folks and actually make progress with your projects?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come to our kickoff meeting on Thursday to discuss starting up this special interest group.  Connect with your fellow hardware geeks and share some of the projects you've been working on. And if we can decide on a name for the SIG, we can set up things like a mailing list, website, and wiki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been kindly granted access to a room at Caltech for this meeting only.  It is a small classroom with about 30 student desks and a teacher desk.  We will have access to a projector and power.  There is an open wireless network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday, September 20, 2012 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
Location: Caltech - Downs 119 (around the corner from usual LUG meeting room)&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Cloning SysAdmins with the Cloud and Juju</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2012/09/13/cloning-sysadmins-with-the-cloud-and-juju/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2012-09-13:2012/09/13/cloning-sysadmins-with-the-cloud-and-juju/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Its time to face the music: There's only a couple guys in Ops, and a
lot of infrastructure to set up and it was all due yesterday. If only
you could clone all the sysadmins of the world to get all of their
expertise and know-how in deploying open source applications, you could
actually get it done. Perhaps there is a way: Juju and Charms! Juju
encapsulates services in a way that promotes sharing and collaboration
the same way packages have done for open source software.  If you are
a sysadmin or a developer who is looking to get an infrastructure of
databases, loadbalancers, and webapps up to speed rapidly, Juju may
be interesting. If you are looking into deploying something massively
scalable, like OpenStack or Hadoop, Juju is built to handle that task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Clint Byrum is a member of the Canonical Ubuntu Server Team, bringing
years of Ops and Development experience in web environments to the task
of making Ubuntu Server shine. &lt;br/&gt;
Date: Thursday, September 13, 2012 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
Location: Caltech - Downs 107&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Kinect Programming</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2012/08/09/kinect-programming/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-08-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2012-08-09:2012/08/09/kinect-programming/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Doug Vargas will talk about programming for the Kinect motion sensing input device by Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Doug Vargas &lt;br/&gt;
Date: Thursday, August 9, 2012 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
Location: Caltech - Downs 107&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Open Discussion July 2012</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2012/07/12/open-discussion-july-2012/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2012-07-12:2012/07/12/open-discussion-july-2012/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;No scheduled speaker. Open discussion continued afterwards at Burger Continental.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will have a brief overview of &lt;a href="http://git-scm.com"&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: You! &lt;br/&gt;
Date: Thursday, July 12, 2012 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
Location: Caltech - Downs 107&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Build your own cloud hosted social network with Ruby on Rails, Git and Heroku</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2012/06/14/build-your-own-cloud-hosted-social-network-with-ruby-on-rails-git-and-heroku/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-06-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2012-06-14:2012/06/14/build-your-own-cloud-hosted-social-network-with-ruby-on-rails-git-and-heroku/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ruby on Rails is an open source framework for developing database driven websites.  Git is a source control management tool.  Heroku is web hosting in the cloud.  In this talk Homan Chou and David Ferril will give a brief overview of each of these tools and give a case study of a real
working social network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Homan Chou and David Ferril &lt;br/&gt;
Date: Thursday, June 14, 2012 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
Location: Caltech - Downs 107&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Rasberry Pi</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2012/05/10/rasberry-pi/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2012-05-10:2012/05/10/rasberry-pi/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Raspberry Pi is a $35, 256MB educational computer that runs Linux.
Dan Kegel will demonstrate how the Pi can be used as a
simple sensor network node, reporting observed Bluetooth
addresses to a central server, running on 4 AA batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Dan Kegel &lt;br/&gt;
Date: Thursday, May 10, 2012 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
Location: Caltech - Downs 107&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Python Web Frameworks - Django and Pylons</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2012/04/12/python-web-frameworks-django-and-pylons/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-04-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2012-04-12:2012/04/12/python-web-frameworks-django-and-pylons/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The two dominant python-based web frameworks are Django and Pylons. They can be used to deploy web applications such as news sites, online ticket tracking systems, or wikis. An overview and comparison of Django and the recently reinvented Pylons Project will be presented. Individual dependencies of the Pylons Project will be described including the Pyramid WSGI engine, the SQLAlchemy database Object Relational Mapper (ORM), and the Mako HTML template generator. A very simple blog engine will be implemented as an instructive example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Braddock Gaskill (braddock .at. braddock.com) &lt;br/&gt;
Date: Thursday, April 12, 2012 @ 7 pm &lt;br/&gt;
Location: Caltech - Downs 107&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>March 2012 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2012/03/08/march-2012-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-03-08T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2012-03-08:2012/03/08/march-2012-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Unity is the new desktop environment for Ubuntu, having first premiered in   &lt;br /&gt;
version 11.04, significantly enhanced with version 11.10, and very much the  &lt;br /&gt;
cornerstone of the upcoming 12.04 release.                                     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A striking departure from Gnome 2, Unity has been seen as a source of        &lt;br /&gt;
controversy in the Linux world.                                                &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will outline some of the design goals that Unity addresses, noting &lt;br /&gt;
strengths, weaknesses, and improvements across the three versions of Ubuntu in 
which it's been included.                                                      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Unity offers many usability affordances, some Ubuntu users prefer to   &lt;br /&gt;
customize it for their specific workflows. Linux is famous for its           &lt;br /&gt;
customizability, and Unity is no exception if you know which tools to look   &lt;br /&gt;
for.                                                                           &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation will outline some of the tools available through the Ubuntu&lt;br /&gt;
Software Center to show you how to customize the Unity interface.              &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker Bio: Richard Gaskin is President of Fourth World, a software design  &lt;br /&gt;
and development consultancy in Los Angeles. Since founding the company in    &lt;br /&gt;
1994, he's developed dozens of commercial and open source applications used by 
a wide range of organizations, including FedEx, AOL, the US Library of       &lt;br /&gt;
Congress, and hundreds of universities around the world.                       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although he started his career with Mac OS, Richard has since delivered      &lt;br /&gt;
applications for Irix, every version of Windows, and has been developing for &lt;br /&gt;
Linux for the last two years.                                                  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard has spoken at more than a dozen tech conferences, including UbuCon,  &lt;br /&gt;
LiveCode Developer Conference, and MacTech where he had the distinction of   &lt;br /&gt;
being the only presenter using Linux.                                          &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday March 8, 2012 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                 &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>February 2012 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2012/02/09/february-2012-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-02-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2012-02-09:2012/02/09/february-2012-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Matt Cambell and Miguel Hernandez will talk about Drupal and their experiences 
with using it to revamp the SGVLUG website.                                    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday February 9, 2012 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>January 2012 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2012/01/12/january-2012-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-01-12T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2012-01-12:2012/01/12/january-2012-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Topic: Horror Stories and Trouble shooting!                                    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is to have a fun meeting with some scary stories and trouble shooting 
lessons to be learned. Depending on how quickly the presentation goes we may &lt;br /&gt;
have time to share more, so please feel free to bring your horror story and  &lt;br /&gt;
what you did to resolve it.                                                    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday January 12, 2012 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>December 2011 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2011/12/08/december-2011-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-12-08T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2011-12-08:2011/12/08/december-2011-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Topic: Virtual Private Servers: On a Budget                                    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christefano who was going to present Redmine is unavailable so we will try to&lt;br /&gt;
reschedule.                                                                    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtual Private Servers: On a Budget - We will discuss a class of virtual    &lt;br /&gt;
private servers available at a low price point allowing individuals to get   &lt;br /&gt;
many of the benefits of dedicated hardware without the cost thanks to        &lt;br /&gt;
virtualization technologies and a competitive marketplace.                     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James McDuffie has worked for JPL for over 10 years and has been using Linux &lt;br /&gt;
since at least kernel version 1.3.                                             &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday December 8, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>November 2011 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2011/11/10/november-2011-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-11-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2011-11-10:2011/11/10/november-2011-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Topic: VPN: Keep the Spies away!                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PPTP (with a demo on DDWRT) along with OpenVPN, L2TP, and IPsec Presenter: Dan 
Buthusiem                                                                      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday November 10, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                             &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>October 2011 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2011/10/13/october-2011-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-10-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2011-10-13:2011/10/13/october-2011-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;SGVLUG meeting 9/8 7-9pm                                                       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Command Line "Tips and Tricks"                                                 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lan Dang spends the majority of her working hours monitoring and             &lt;br /&gt;
troubleshooting data processing systems on Linux-based computer clusters. She&lt;br /&gt;
has accumulated a number of tips and tricks to deal with the command line. Her 
arsenal includes: GNU screen, awk, sed, shell scripting, remote ssh command  &lt;br /&gt;
execution, bash command history, and a variety of system utilities. This talk&lt;br /&gt;
will cover useful one-liners and the small set of useful commands that will  &lt;br /&gt;
get you started using these tools or using them in new ways. Whether you're a&lt;br /&gt;
newbie or a command line guru, you'll probably pick up something useful for  &lt;br /&gt;
the next time you're at the command line.                                      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday October 13, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>September 2011 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2011/09/08/september-2011-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-09-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2011-09-08:2011/09/08/september-2011-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;SGVLUG meeting 9/8 7-9pm                                                       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topic: Disaster Recovery and Backups in the era of the cloud Presentation and&lt;br /&gt;
Discussion                                                                     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please bring your questions, opinions, and solutions for discussion!           &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday September 8, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                             &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>August 2011 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2011/08/11/august-2011-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-08-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2011-08-11:2011/08/11/august-2011-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monthly Meeting.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Topic: Virtualmin / Webmin + Brief review Defcon/Blackhat:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take your Drupal sites to the next level with the free, open-source Webmin   &lt;br /&gt;
control panel and its powerful Virtualmin plug-in. Add as many features as you 
want, including unlimited domains, mail accounts, Subversion repositories,   &lt;br /&gt;
mailing lists, and more with a point-and-click web interface.                  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Webmin and Virtualmin are similar to cPanel and WHM, respectively, and can   &lt;br /&gt;
manage dozens or even hundreds of domains. They are the perfect tools for    &lt;br /&gt;
creating test and development sites, hosting client websites or even managing&lt;br /&gt;
a full-blown online infrastructure for running a business.                     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did we forget to mention, Webmin and Virtualmin are free* and open-source?   &lt;br /&gt;
Compared to site licensing costs of cPanel, WHM, Plesk and other proprietary &lt;br /&gt;
control panels, Webmin and Virtualmin cost only as much as a basic           &lt;br /&gt;
$10-20/month VPS account.                                                      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bio: ----- Christefano is CEO and Co-founder of Exaltation of Larks, where   &lt;br /&gt;
Virtualmin has been a key ingredient for rapid website deployment. He is a   &lt;br /&gt;
sysadmin for LA Drupal and the DrupalCamp LA website (which uses Virtualmin) &lt;br /&gt;
and has been on the Drupal.org and groups.drupal.org webmaster teams since   &lt;br /&gt;
2008. Exaltation of Larks, which provides Drupal consulting, development and &lt;br /&gt;
training http://www.larks.la                                                   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday August 11, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                               &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>July 2011 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2011/07/14/july-2011-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2011-07-14:2011/07/14/july-2011-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monthly meeting.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;APRS is a amateur radio network where small packets of data such as position &lt;br /&gt;
reports, messages or telemetry are transmitted to other radio operators and  &lt;br /&gt;
eventually propagated to the Internet.                                       &lt;br /&gt;
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automatic_Packet_Reporting_System                 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proliferation of small, low power and easily hackable ARM devices opens up 
many possibilities for setting up unobtrusive computing solutions. Amateur   &lt;br /&gt;
radio operator and long time Linux user James McDuffie (K6JLM) explores using&lt;br /&gt;
the Seagate GoFlex Net along with surplus amateur radio equipment to build a &lt;br /&gt;
APRS digipeater for helping to relay packets both over RF and to the Internet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday July 14, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                 &lt;br /&gt;
Location: 107 Downs Lab                                     &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>June 2011 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2011/06/09/june-2011-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-06-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2011-06-09:2011/06/09/june-2011-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Caltech team participating in the U.S. Department of Energy 2011 Solar   &lt;br /&gt;
Decathlon will present their project, for which they are using various       &lt;br /&gt;
open-source technology.                                                        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The Solar Decathlon is a U.S. Department of Energy Sponsored competition    &lt;br /&gt;
which challenges teams of college and graduate students from around the world&lt;br /&gt;
to design and build solar-powered, net-zero houses. Inside the SCI-Arc/Caltech 
entry, code named CHIP, a sophisticated home automation system monitors every&lt;br /&gt;
watt of electricity consumed and visually communicates the information to    &lt;br /&gt;
homeowners. It also plays a central role in optimizing the behavior of the   &lt;br /&gt;
house at all times, such as by controlling operation of the active thermal   &lt;br /&gt;
mass, shutting down appliances or lights that are no longer used, and of     &lt;br /&gt;
course giving the homeowners an instant understanding into how their own     &lt;br /&gt;
behaviors affects their energy use and in turn their energy bill."             &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://chip2011.com/                                                           &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday June 9, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                  &lt;br /&gt;
Location: 107 Downs Lab                                     &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>May 2011 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2011/05/12/may-2011-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-05-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2011-05-12:2011/05/12/may-2011-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monthly Meeting.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday May 12, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                  &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>April 2011 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2011/04/14/april-2011-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-04-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2011-04-14:2011/04/14/april-2011-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Topic: Todd CC will discuss the impact of a world with rapidly changing      &lt;br /&gt;
technologies, radical fluctuations in staffing needs, and changes in the     &lt;br /&gt;
employer/employee dynamic and how you can be best prepared for your next job &lt;br /&gt;
and/or career. During this presentation, the relatively new catchphrase      &lt;br /&gt;
"DevOps" will be discussed as it pertains to job advancement and career      &lt;br /&gt;
opportunities.                                                                 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presenter: Cranston-Cuebas, Todd With 13 years of experience in technology   &lt;br /&gt;
staffing in Los Angeles, Todd has been through the dot-com boom and bust, the&lt;br /&gt;
housing boom and subsequent recession, and through it all, has kept a close  &lt;br /&gt;
eye on employment trends in technology.                                        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday April 14, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                &lt;br /&gt;
Location: 107 Downs Lab                                     &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>March 2011 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2011/03/10/march-2011-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2011-03-10:2011/03/10/march-2011-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monthly Meeting.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday March 10, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>February 2011 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2011/02/10/february-2011-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-02-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2011-02-10:2011/02/10/february-2011-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monthly Meeting.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topic: How to program your own smart phone Matthew Campbell and Rae Yip will &lt;br /&gt;
walk us through the steps needed to get a basic "hello world" application on &lt;br /&gt;
an Android phone.                                                              &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuation from the January meeting.                                         &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew will cover the following: Android programming overview. Installing the 
development environment (Eclipse 3.5.2), the Android SDK and the Eclipse ADT &lt;br /&gt;
development tools. Writing your first hello world application. Compiling and &lt;br /&gt;
emulating the application. Installing the application on your phone. Using the 
Google APIs. Publishing your application.                                      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rae will cover more details of the Android operating system including the    &lt;br /&gt;
filesystem layout third party libraries Open Intents                           &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday February 10, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                             &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>January 2011 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2011/01/13/january-2011-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2011-01-13:2011/01/13/january-2011-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monthly Meeting.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topic: How to program your own smart phone Matthew Campbell and Rae Yip will &lt;br /&gt;
walk us through the steps needed to get a basic "hello world" application on &lt;br /&gt;
an Android phone.                                                              &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew will cover the following: Android programming overview. Installing the 
development environment (Eclipse 3.5.2), the Android SDK and the Eclipse ADT &lt;br /&gt;
development tools. Writing your first hello world application. Compiling and &lt;br /&gt;
emulating the application. Installing the application on your phone. Using the 
Google APIs. Publishing your application.                                      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rae will cover more details of the Android operating system including the    &lt;br /&gt;
filesystem layout third party libraries Open Intents                           &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday January 13, 2011 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>December 2010 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2010/12/09/december-2010-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-12-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2010-12-09:2010/12/09/december-2010-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Steven will be doing a presentation on "Software Complexity."                  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday December 9, 2010 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>November 2010 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2010/11/11/november-2010-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-11-11T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2010-11-11:2010/11/11/november-2010-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dan Kegel will show off a bunch of popular games running on Linux and explain&lt;br /&gt;
how to install them. This will be a very informal event and will last about 30 
minutes, plus questions.                                                       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday November 11, 2010 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                             &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>October 2010 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2010/10/14/october-2010-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-10-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2010-10-14:2010/10/14/october-2010-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Filling the Digital Divide with Offline Content: Six ways to deliver a library 
anywhere for under $90                                                         &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SUMMARY                                                                        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Off-line content is reading material, educational texts, and other reference &lt;br /&gt;
materials delivered on media such as SDCards, DVDs, custom hardware, or hard &lt;br /&gt;
drives so that it can be used without internet access. A typical deployment  &lt;br /&gt;
can deliver the equivalent of tens of thousands of printed books. The cost to&lt;br /&gt;
deliver large off-line libraries has fallen below the cost to deliver online &lt;br /&gt;
internet access in most areas. Off-line content thus provides a cost effective 
way to provide access to the world's knowledge before affordable internet    &lt;br /&gt;
infrastructure is available. This presentation reviews six emerging projects &lt;br /&gt;
which aim to provide off-line hardware and libraries, including the author's &lt;br /&gt;
creation, the $20 Humane Reader                                                &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Braddock Gaskill is CEO and co-founder of Dockside Vision Inc, an advanced   &lt;br /&gt;
information visualization and human-computer interface company. Prior to     &lt;br /&gt;
founding Dockside Vision, Mr. Gaskill had over ten years of experience as a  &lt;br /&gt;
technology consultant in both the defense and commercial sectors. His        &lt;br /&gt;
expertise spans the fields of information visualization, collaborative       &lt;br /&gt;
systems, electronics design, machine vision, information assurance, and      &lt;br /&gt;
robotics control, and includes publications in ballistics simulation, a patent 
in crytographic authentication, and multiple pending patents in visualization&lt;br /&gt;
techniques.                                                                    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday October 14, 2010 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>September 2010 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2010/09/09/september-2010-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-09-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2010-09-09:2010/09/09/september-2010-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monthly meeting                                                                &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday September 9, 2010 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                             &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>August 2010 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2010/08/12/august-2010-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-08-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2010-08-12:2010/08/12/august-2010-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Simone Bernacchia will be speaking about AROS which is a free and open source&lt;br /&gt;
implementation of the AmigaOS.                                                 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday August 12, 2010 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                               &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>July 2010 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2010/07/08/july-2010-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-07-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2010-07-08:2010/07/08/july-2010-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Topic: "NoSQL" practical experience: use of Hadoop, Cassandra, CouchDB, and  &lt;br /&gt;
other open source distributed technologies instead of relational databases.  &lt;br /&gt;
When to use SQL and when to not use it.                                        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presenter: Michael Lum Head of Engineering at OpenX.org Prior to that Michael&lt;br /&gt;
was the Director of Architecture for the Search and Advertising Technology   &lt;br /&gt;
Group at Yahoo, the group responsible for web search, sponsored search, and  &lt;br /&gt;
display advertising, and was the group that incubated grid computing         &lt;br /&gt;
technologies such as Hadoop, ZooKeeper and YTS (Yahoo Traffic Server). Michael 
joined Yahoo via the Overture acquisition. He has work experience from IBM and 
various startup companies.                                                     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday July 8, 2010 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                  &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>June 2010 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2010/06/10/june-2010-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2010-06-10:2010/06/10/june-2010-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monthly meeting.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday June 10, 2010 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                 &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>May 2010 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2010/05/13/may-2010-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2010-05-13:2010/05/13/may-2010-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monthly meeting.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topic: Business and design of open source products, Version 2                  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bio: Stephan Cunningham is the Head of Product and Market Design for OpenX.  &lt;br /&gt;
OpenX builds both open source and proprietary digital advertising            &lt;br /&gt;
technologies. Prior to joining OpenX he held product and engineering roles at&lt;br /&gt;
Yahoo!, The New York Times, and IBM Microelectronics.                          &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday May 13, 2010 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                  &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>April 2010 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2010/04/08/april-2010-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-04-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2010-04-08:2010/04/08/april-2010-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monthly meeting.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;April 2010: An open-source 8-bit computer to save the world Braddock is back!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Braddock Gaskill will discuss and debut his open source hardware and software&lt;br /&gt;
project designed both for hobbyists and as an e-book reader for developing   &lt;br /&gt;
nations.                                                                       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The device can store a 5,000 book library or the better part of Wikipedia and&lt;br /&gt;
display it on any TV set in a developing-world village library - all for under 
$20. It is also a fun general purpose 8-bit computing platform comparable in &lt;br /&gt;
raw capability to the Apple II and built, in part, for experimentation and   &lt;br /&gt;
hobbyists. The entire system is open sourced, and uses GNU toolchain cross   &lt;br /&gt;
development under Linux with heavy OSS throughout.                             &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation will work through the design, schematic, PCB fab, assembly, &lt;br /&gt;
and software dev. Braddock will walk the audience through each stage, cover  &lt;br /&gt;
which tools were used, ponder major design considerations, and pay special   &lt;br /&gt;
attention to open source solutions.                                            &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday April 8, 2010 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                 &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>March 2010 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2010/03/11/march-2010-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-03-11T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2010-03-11:2010/03/11/march-2010-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monthly meeting.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topic: Data Ownership - How I (mostly) wrestled control of my data from evil &lt;br /&gt;
corporate overlords                                                            &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Charles N Wyble                                                       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles Wyble is a systems and security engineer. His focus in 2010 is       &lt;br /&gt;
security research, with a particular emphasis on improving performance of    &lt;br /&gt;
automated analytic systems. In support of this, he does a lot of networking  &lt;br /&gt;
stuff and is in the process of building a malware lab.                         &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He lives in sunny southern California, with his wife Patricia and 2 dogs ISIS&lt;br /&gt;
and OSPF. Yes they are named after routing protocols. He frequently hosts    &lt;br /&gt;
hacker parties, where all sorts of cool stuff gets built. You will often find&lt;br /&gt;
him at various hot startups doing consulting, and at numerous user group     &lt;br /&gt;
meetings throughout the southwestern United States.                            &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles Wyble will be joining the SGVLUG group once again and discussing the &lt;br /&gt;
topic of data ownership / private cloud.                                       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Owning ones data is a critical and often overlooked part of security. As such, 
he will discuss how he maintains numerous web properties on a Linux server at&lt;br /&gt;
his residence, connected to the best DSL ATT has to offer.                     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has recently completed moving all his data onto his own server, freeing it&lt;br /&gt;
(mostly) from the control of google,yahoo etc. It was a relatively           &lt;br /&gt;
straightforward process, encompassing 4 major phases. He will talk about the &lt;br /&gt;
tools he utilizes, and advantages/disadvantages to his setup and some of the &lt;br /&gt;
problems he encountered.                                                       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday March 11, 2010 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>February 2010 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2010/02/11/february-2010-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-02-11T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2010-02-11:2010/02/11/february-2010-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monthly meeting.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topic: Internet security for the rest of us                                    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Rae Yip                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday February 11, 2010 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                             &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>January 2010 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2010/01/14/january-2010-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2010-01-14:2010/01/14/january-2010-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Case Study in Open Source Software Development                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For three years the speaker ran a small technology startup company developing&lt;br /&gt;
new ways of visualizing and exploring huge datasets, like, for example, the  &lt;br /&gt;
entire routing structure of the internet, or tens of thousands of documents.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover real-world experiences with the broad variety of Open   &lt;br /&gt;
Source software which made the project possible. Dependencies included Boost,&lt;br /&gt;
CMake, OpenSceneGraph, khtml, gecko, Firefox plugins, GraphViz, lighttpd,    &lt;br /&gt;
Xerces DOM, and more. Theses building blocks were in many cases pushed to (and 
beyond) their limits, deployed in a cross-platform Linux and Windows         &lt;br /&gt;
environment, and compiled with GCC and MSVC++. We will cover lessons learned,&lt;br /&gt;
better alternatives, and other findings.                                       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Braddock Gaskill is CEO and co-founder of Dockside Vision Inc, an advanced   &lt;br /&gt;
information visualization and human-computer interface company. Prior to     &lt;br /&gt;
founding Dockside Vision, Mr. Gaskill had over ten years of experience as a  &lt;br /&gt;
technology consultant in both the defense and commercial sectors. His        &lt;br /&gt;
expertise spans the fields of information visualization, collaborative       &lt;br /&gt;
systems, machine vision, information assurance, and robotics control, and    &lt;br /&gt;
includes publications in ballistics simulation, a patent in cryptographic    &lt;br /&gt;
authentication, and multiple pending patents in visualization techniques.      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday January 14, 2010 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>December 2009 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2009/12/10/december-2009-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-12-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2009-12-10:2009/12/10/december-2009-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If the FC12 speaker is not available, the topic will probably be about       &lt;br /&gt;
security in general.                                                           &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday December 10, 2009 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                             &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>November 2009 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2009/11/12/november-2009-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-11-12T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2009-11-12:2009/11/12/november-2009-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Topic for November: Answering the Northrup Grumman Lunar Lander X PRIZE      &lt;br /&gt;
Challenge                                                                      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Northrup Grumman Lunar Lander X Prize Challenge, a NASA space competition&lt;br /&gt;
prize contest, is intended to foster the commercial development of a vehicle &lt;br /&gt;
capable of launching from the surface of the moon into lunar orbit and then  &lt;br /&gt;
land back on the moon. Consisting of two levels of difficulty, a prize is    &lt;br /&gt;
given to the 1st and 2nd place winners of each level. Unreasonable Rocket, one 
of three teams that competed at this year's event, attempted to claim purses &lt;br /&gt;
from both competition levels.                                                  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come listen to the team from Unreasonable Rocket share their experience in   &lt;br /&gt;
this year's event.                                                             &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday November 12, 2009 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                             &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>October 2009 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2009/10/08/october-2009-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-10-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2009-10-08:2009/10/08/october-2009-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Topic: Open Street Map: What, Why, and How                                     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by: Blars Blarson, from Open Street Map                              &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday October 8, 2009 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                               &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>September 2009 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2009/09/10/september-2009-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-09-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2009-09-10:2009/09/10/september-2009-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday September 10, 2009 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                            &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>August 2009 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2009/08/13/august-2009-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-08-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2009-08-13:2009/08/13/august-2009-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Possible topics include Defcon.                                                &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday August 13, 2009 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                               &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>July 2009 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2009/07/09/july-2009-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-07-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2009-07-09:2009/07/09/july-2009-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Topic summary: Fedora 11, code named Leonidas, is the latest offering from   &lt;br /&gt;
Fedora. With over 60 improvements and new features, Fedora 11 will be        &lt;br /&gt;
demonstrated at the meeting.                                                   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the speaker: Larry Cafiero is the Regional Ambassador for the U.S. West&lt;br /&gt;
Coast for the Fedora Project. He is also a senior partner at Redwood Digital &lt;br /&gt;
Research in Felton, California (Santa Cruz County), which is a small         &lt;br /&gt;
business/SOHO computer maintenance and networking firm utilizing FOSS        &lt;br /&gt;
programs. He also blogs as "Larry the Free Software Guy" at                  &lt;br /&gt;
http://larrythefreesoftwareguy.wordpress.com.                                  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday July 9, 2009 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                  &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>June 2009 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2009/06/11/june-2009-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-06-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2009-06-11:2009/06/11/june-2009-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Linux Virtual Server by Solomon Chang                                          &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WordPress plugin by Braydon Fuller (time permitting)                           &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solomon is a MySQL certified DBA and the current acting director of LAMPSIG. &lt;br /&gt;
He works as a professional Database Administrator for Vantage Media in El    &lt;br /&gt;
Segundo, and is a co-author of the MySQL Cluster Certification Study Guide.  &lt;br /&gt;
When he's not pulling all-nighters in the office, he plays piano, poker, and &lt;br /&gt;
Warhammer 40K, although not always all at the same time.                       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday June 11, 2009 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                 &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>April 2009 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2009/04/09/april-2009-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-04-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2009-04-09:2009/04/09/april-2009-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Looking for a new tech related job? Want to get a peek into the head of a    &lt;br /&gt;
headhunter? Come listen to Todd Cranston-Cuebas talk about the current state &lt;br /&gt;
of the job market in the Los Angeles area, with a special emphasis on tech   &lt;br /&gt;
roles and how to land that perfect job.                                        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todd Cranston-Cuebas has been leading technology hiring at Ticketmaster for  &lt;br /&gt;
over 5 years. He specializes in working with candidates with a background in &lt;br /&gt;
open-source tools and technologies. He has spoken at BOF sessions at a number&lt;br /&gt;
of large technology conferences including ApacheCon, OSCON, USENIX, and of   &lt;br /&gt;
course at SGVLUG meetings!                                                     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday April 9, 2009 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                 &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>March 2009 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2009/03/12/march-2009-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-03-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2009-03-12:2009/03/12/march-2009-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Learn and Discuss Linux security and forensics issues.                         &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the computer novice to the computer expert, we hope to make this meeting&lt;br /&gt;
useful for everyone. Novices, please be prepared to take notes and follow up &lt;br /&gt;
with references. Experts, please bring us your favorite Linux computer       &lt;br /&gt;
references/tips, as we plan to have a very active discussion.                  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bio: Matti has been working in the computer industry since the 1980s and has &lt;br /&gt;
been responsible for IT infrastructure and mission critical operations for   &lt;br /&gt;
nearly two decades, and has attended more conferences on IT                  &lt;br /&gt;
operations/security than he can remember.                                      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday March 12, 2009 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>February 2009 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2009/02/12/february-2009-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-02-12T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2009-02-12:2009/02/12/february-2009-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a talk called "Mapping Wireless Access Points," Peter J. Sprenger will talk 
about making a small toughbook into a Linux car navigation system. He also   &lt;br /&gt;
enabled GPS integration to enhance wireless access point findings by combining 
GPS information with a Google map overlay and Kismet data dumps to map out   &lt;br /&gt;
existing wireless access points.                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sprenger has used Linux for the past 13 years. Currently running LFS as main &lt;br /&gt;
desktop system, with a FreeBSD shell server and Slackware Media PC. He is    &lt;br /&gt;
leads a Cal Poly team for CCDC (Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition),       &lt;br /&gt;
concentrating in network defense. Special attention to security research and &lt;br /&gt;
Information Warfare studies with experience in several different continents  &lt;br /&gt;
performing missions occasionally oriented in that direction.                   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday February 12, 2009 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                             &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>December 2008 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2008/12/11/december-2008-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-12-11T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2008-12-11:2008/12/11/december-2008-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a talk called "How to Crack WEP and WPA Using Debian GNU/Linux," Jeff     &lt;br /&gt;
Henbest, the president of Cal Poly SWIFT of California State Polytechnic     &lt;br /&gt;
University, Pomona, will explain the easy of cracking WEP and WPA using tools&lt;br /&gt;
available on linux. Information: http://cppswift.ath.cx/meetings/wepwpa.html . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday December 11, 2008 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                             &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>November 2008 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2008/11/13/november-2008-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-11-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2008-11-13:2008/11/13/november-2008-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;"Shakin' It up at Caltech" Rae Yip and Shang-Lin will give an overview of the&lt;br /&gt;
open-source software in use at the Caltech Seismology Lab.                     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday November 13, 2008 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                             &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>October 2008 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2008/10/09/october-2008-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-10-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2008-10-09:2008/10/09/october-2008-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Eric Hammond will be leading an Amazon EC2 Beginners Workshop. EC2 is Amazon's 
Elastic Compute Cloud that provides virtual Linux computers rented by the    &lt;br /&gt;
hour. (http://aws.amazon.com/ec2)                                              &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This workshop will provide a brief overview/intro to EC2 followed by a       &lt;br /&gt;
step-by-step walkthrough to creating an Amazon EC2 account and starting your &lt;br /&gt;
first EC2 instance (server) running Ubuntu, Debian, Fedora, or CentOS (others&lt;br /&gt;
may also be available).                                                        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bring a laptop and a credit card with the ability to charge up to $0.25 in EC2 
service fees.                                                                  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eric is a veteran EC2 user, maintains a popular series of Ubuntu and Debian  &lt;br /&gt;
machine images for EC2 at http://alestic.com and fosters a global EC2 Ubuntu &lt;br /&gt;
community at http://groups.google.com/group/ec2ubuntu.                         &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday October 9, 2008 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                               &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>September 2008 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2008/09/11/september-2008-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-09-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2008-09-11:2008/09/11/september-2008-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Michael Proctor-Smith will give an update on MythTV (the Mythical Convergence&lt;br /&gt;
Box), the open-source alternative to TiVo or Windows Media Center. More than &lt;br /&gt;
just a digital VCR, which provides basic "time shifting" capability, Digital &lt;br /&gt;
Video Recorders change the way people watch television by providing the      &lt;br /&gt;
ability to pause live TV, instantly replay interesting scenes, and skip      &lt;br /&gt;
commercials. With an up-to-date TV schedule, the DVR can automatically record&lt;br /&gt;
shows based on user preferences.                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael will talk about his strange MythTV setup and a small portion of      &lt;br /&gt;
MythTV's features including Recording HDTV, streaming to a Cell Phone and    &lt;br /&gt;
using an AppleTV as a MythTV Front-end.                                        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Runs The San Gabriel Valley Linux(R) Users Group (At least he has been 
told that by others). He spends an unhealthy amount of his time watching     &lt;br /&gt;
MythTV and plotting how he can never be without access to MythTV.              &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday September 11, 2008 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                            &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>August 2008 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2008/08/14/august-2008-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2008-08-14:2008/08/14/august-2008-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu is the said to be the biggest thing in desktop Linux at the moment, but 
Neal and Nathan are here to cut through the hype and show you how Ubuntu can &lt;br /&gt;
simplify your life and make your computer more fun and simple to use for     &lt;br /&gt;
everyday tasks. They will discuss various aspects of Ubuntu, from the basics &lt;br /&gt;
of everyday system maintenance to how to customize your system. They will also 
cover the differences that make Ubuntu unique from Debian and other distros; &lt;br /&gt;
and the differences and benefits of the various flavors that make up the     &lt;br /&gt;
Ubuntu family.                                                                 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nathan Haines is a computer consultant and instructor who enjoys programming &lt;br /&gt;
in Python and is a member of the California Ubuntu LoCo team. Neal Bussett is&lt;br /&gt;
an Electrical Engineer and leader of the California Ubuntu LoCo team. Both are 
Ubuntu Members and advocates of Free software.                                 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday August 14, 2008 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                               &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>July 2008 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2008/07/10/july-2008-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-07-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2008-07-10:2008/07/10/july-2008-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a presentation called "Geotagging with Linux and Free Software," Tom      &lt;br /&gt;
Emerson will describe geotagging, the process of adding geographical         &lt;br /&gt;
information to images, which can later be searched. Emerson will show how he &lt;br /&gt;
has geotagged photos from his recent vacation and can search for them using  &lt;br /&gt;
various search engines, including Google Earth.                                &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday July 10, 2008 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                 &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>June 2008 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2008/06/12/june-2008-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-06-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2008-06-12:2008/06/12/june-2008-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday June 12, 2008 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                 &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>May 2008 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2008/05/08/may-2008-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-05-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2008-05-08:2008/05/08/may-2008-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wilfred Nilsen will present the BarracudaDrive, a secure Web application server 
for the Linksys NSLU2 (Network Storage Link for USB 2.0 Disk Drives) using the&lt;br /&gt;
Unslung Linux firmware replacement. Using an external USB Flash memory for    &lt;br /&gt;
storing the database files, it should be possible to create an application    &lt;br /&gt;
server that is virtually maintenance free.                                      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wilfred will be here to give a demo of the NSLU2 running BarracudaDrive,      &lt;br /&gt;
including the many practical features of BarracudaDrive and how some users use&lt;br /&gt;
BarracudaDrive for many non traditional Web server tasks.                       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the BarracudaDrive for Linksys NSLU2                    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://barracudadrive.net/blog/2008/03/BarracudaDrive-for-Linksys-NSLU2.        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the presenter:                                                            &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With over 15 years experience as a software engineer, Wilfred Nilsen is a part&lt;br /&gt;
owner of Real Time Logic which provides software tools for embedded software  &lt;br /&gt;
engineers. He has been working on the Barracuda Embedded Application Server   &lt;br /&gt;
since 2001.                                                                     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.sgvlug.org/index.php?option=com_content&amp;amp;task=view&amp;amp;id=97&amp;amp;Itemid=27. 
Date: Thursday May 8, 2008 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                    &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                          &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>April 2008 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2008/04/10/april-2008-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-04-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2008-04-10:2008/04/10/april-2008-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Charles Wyble has his hand in many pots - running LiLAX, installing wireless &lt;br /&gt;
for all of L.A., and teaching "open source" using "moodle," which is a free  &lt;br /&gt;
software e-learning platform.                                                  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles Wyble is a systems engineer with 7 years of experience. He runs a    &lt;br /&gt;
professional services firm called Known Element Enterprises and has          &lt;br /&gt;
contributed to a number of high profile open source projects                 &lt;br /&gt;
(OpenOffice/Wine/Gnumeric) and proprietary software (most notably VmWare     &lt;br /&gt;
Workstation).                                                                  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday April 10, 2008 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>March 2008 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2008/03/13/march-2008-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-03-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2008-03-13:2008/03/13/march-2008-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ronald Stewart, creative director of the Trinity Audio Group will speak at the 
next San Gabriel Valley Linux User Group. He will present the                &lt;br /&gt;
yet-to-be-released InDaMixx appliance, a full-featured, hand-held recording  &lt;br /&gt;
studio built on Linux (a customized version of 64Studio, to be more specific). 
He will go over topics such as why Linux was chosen, the future of music in  &lt;br /&gt;
the open-source community and will demo some of the great features of        &lt;br /&gt;
InDaMixx.                                                                      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ronald's background in the music industry goes back to the late 80's as a DJ &amp;amp; 
Remixer for Factor 3 Records, Tommy Boy Records, Bullet Proof Records &amp;amp; one of 
the first beta testers for Digidesign's Pro Tools. Ronald decided that he    &lt;br /&gt;
needed a full-featured device that he could take with him, along with all his&lt;br /&gt;
music only to find out nothing like this existed. Ever the frontiersman,     &lt;br /&gt;
Ronald decided to blaze the trail, chose all open-source applications and    &lt;br /&gt;
hasn't looked back ever since.                                                 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday March 13, 2008 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>February 2008 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2008/02/14/february-2008-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-02-14T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2008-02-14:2008/02/14/february-2008-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Chris got his kid an "OLPC" laptop and thinks he can wrestle it away from him&lt;br /&gt;
long enough for some "show-n-tell"...                                          &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OLPC is the "One Laptop Per Child" initiative, aimed at providing full-fledged 
laptop computers to every child in developing nations. Their goal is for a   &lt;br /&gt;
$100/unit price point, and they are quite close (actually, the price is about&lt;br /&gt;
$150)                                                                          &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday February 14, 2008 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                             &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>January 2008 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2008/01/10/january-2008-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-01-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2008-01-10:2008/01/10/january-2008-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dan Kegel of Google, a longtime Linux user and developer, will present a     &lt;br /&gt;
grab-bag of interesting topics:                                              &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt; Quick Picasa 2.7 for Linux demo. (Picasa is Google's photo management    &lt;br /&gt;
  software for Windows and Linux, but many people don't know about the Linux 
  version)                                                                 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt; Quick Wine status report. (Wine is Linux's implementation of Win32; it   &lt;br /&gt;
  lets you run many Windows applications.)                                 &lt;br /&gt;
* Introduction to Zumastor. (Zumastor is Linux's answer to ZFS, kind of; it&lt;br /&gt;
  lets you take atomic snapshots of any filesystem, and easily replicate   &lt;br /&gt;
  those snapshots to remote systems.)                                        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan is a developer for all three projects and was elected the release manager&lt;br /&gt;
for the upcoming 1.0 release of Wine, so feel free to ask all the technical  &lt;br /&gt;
questions you like.                                                            &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday January 10, 2008 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>November 2007 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2007/11/08/november-2007-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-11-08T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2007-11-08:2007/11/08/november-2007-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Asterisk is an open-source PBX program that provides automatic call          &lt;br /&gt;
distribution, voice mail and interactive voice response menus. X10 is a      &lt;br /&gt;
power-line carrier protocol for controlling lights and appliances. What can  &lt;br /&gt;
you do when you combine them? Claude Felizardo will give us an update on his &lt;br /&gt;
home-automation system and how integrating Asterisk has moved his home closer&lt;br /&gt;
to what is depicted in popular science fiction.                                &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With over 15 years as a Unix developer, Claude got his start with Linux in the 
late 90s when he built his own firewall. Most of his friends and family think&lt;br /&gt;
he has too many gadgets, but he's always looking for something new to play   &lt;br /&gt;
with, especially if it can be integrated into his system at home. His previous 
presentations include an Intro to Home Automation, Hacking TiVo and Monitoring 
the Weather with Linux.                                                        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday November 8, 2007 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>October 2007 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2007/10/11/october-2007-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-10-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2007-10-11:2007/10/11/october-2007-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Kris Bergstrom will give an introduction to the extremely powerful LaTeX     &lt;br /&gt;
typesetting system and its application to real-world document production. He &lt;br /&gt;
will explain how he uses it in the creation of essays, books, and letters    &lt;br /&gt;
incorporating graphics. He will also demonstrate the use of LaTeX in his     &lt;br /&gt;
band's annual fund drive which requires the creation of personalized letters &lt;br /&gt;
(mail merge) and envelopes.                                                    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially designed to typeset mathematical formulae, the LaTeX system        &lt;br /&gt;
incorporates world-class fonts with international symbols. The system        &lt;br /&gt;
successfully handles the automatic typesetting of complicated textbooks with &lt;br /&gt;
thousands of images and internal page, chapter, and figure references. The   &lt;br /&gt;
line-breaking algorithm used by LaTeX (or more accurately, by the more basic &lt;br /&gt;
TeX engine) is the industry leader (eventually adopted by Adobe for its      &lt;br /&gt;
commercial program, InDesign).                                                 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the presenter:                                                         &lt;br /&gt;
Kris Bergstrom was first exposed to GNU/Linux in electronic music courses at &lt;br /&gt;
Stanford's Center for Computer Research in Music and Acoustics. In 2000,     &lt;br /&gt;
excited by the ideals of Free Software, he tried to switch his desktop from  &lt;br /&gt;
Windows to Debian but with limited knowledge of networking and basic admin   &lt;br /&gt;
tasks, was unable to get a basic system up and running. Soon after moving to &lt;br /&gt;
Los Angeles in 2002, he joined a Linux Users Group and found the support he  &lt;br /&gt;
needed to do all his personal and business computer tasks with free software.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday October 11, 2007 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>September 2007 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2007/09/13/september-2007-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2007-09-13:2007/09/13/september-2007-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Kerry Garrison is back to demo the new trixbox Pro product from Fonality. This 
latest incarnation uses the hybrid-hosted model developed by Fonality for    &lt;br /&gt;
PBXtra, but gives installers the control over the hardware and phone         &lt;br /&gt;
provisioning that they enjoy with trixbox CE.                                  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kerry Garrison has been in the IT industry for over 20 years with positions  &lt;br /&gt;
ranging from IT Director of a large multi-site distribution company to       &lt;br /&gt;
developing a large hosted web server platform for a major ISP, to running his&lt;br /&gt;
own IT consulting business in Southern California. Kerry was introduced to the 
world of Asterisk by a friend and began installing Asterisk-based phone      &lt;br /&gt;
systems for his small business clients. He wrote articles about Asterisk and &lt;br /&gt;
trixbox that became extremely popular on the net, and eventually published the 
definitive book on trixbox, "trixbox Made Easy." Today, Kerry is the senior  &lt;br /&gt;
product development manager for trixbox at Fonality. Kerry regularly speaks at 
trade shows, user groups, and radio programs. He is also the publisher of both 
http://www.voipspeak.net and http://www.asterisktutorials.com. Kerry is an   &lt;br /&gt;
avid amateur photographer who writes tutorials and product reviews for his   &lt;br /&gt;
photography blog site at http://L7Foto.com.                                    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday September 13, 2007 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                            &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>August 2007 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2007/08/09/august-2007-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-08-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2007-08-09:2007/08/09/august-2007-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;X509 and SSL are complicated topics. While they share the basic PKI          &lt;br /&gt;
infrastructure that PGP and others do, X509 (and SSL by extension) are more  &lt;br /&gt;
complicated. Extending beyond the basic encryption, signing, decryption, and &lt;br /&gt;
verification of basic PKI, X509 includes a variety of extra pieces and       &lt;br /&gt;
information enabling more features. This talk will cover what X509 and SSL   &lt;br /&gt;
are, how they relate, how to use them, and how to learn more. It will discuss&lt;br /&gt;
PKI from both an certificate end-user perspective as well as from a          &lt;br /&gt;
Certificate Authority perspective. If time permits, a small comparison to PGP&lt;br /&gt;
will also be included akin to the one at the end of my PGP talk.               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phil Dibowitz is a Senior UNIX Systems Administrator for the Web Systems team&lt;br /&gt;
at Ticketmaster. Web Systems manages the Ticketmaster.com infrastructure:    &lt;br /&gt;
roughly 2000 linux systems organized in four independent, redundant, and     &lt;br /&gt;
geographically separate clusters across the US. Phil has worked in IT for 9  &lt;br /&gt;
years and has worked as a Linux, Solaris, and Network Administrator, and has a 
BS in Computer Engineering and Computer Science from USC. He is also the     &lt;br /&gt;
author of iptstate(8), mime_dump(1), and check_x509(1), co-founder of the MSS&lt;br /&gt;
Initiative, and works on IP Filter and the USB Storage driver in the linux   &lt;br /&gt;
kernel. Find out more about Phil Dibowitz at http://www.phildev.net/           &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday August 9, 2007 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>July 2007 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2007/07/12/july-2007-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-07-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2007-07-12:2007/07/12/july-2007-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday July 12, 2007 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                 &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>June 2007 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2007/06/14/june-2007-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-06-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2007-06-14:2007/06/14/june-2007-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At this meeting Thomas Chung will give a short presentation on the "State of &lt;br /&gt;
the Fedora Project and FC7." Chung is a Fedora Ambassador for Southern       &lt;br /&gt;
California and has worked on such projects as Open Webmail, OpenAFS, Mplayer &lt;br /&gt;
plug-in, X-CD-Roast, QEMU and the Helix Player.                                &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday June 14, 2007 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                 &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>May 2007 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2007/05/10/may-2007-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2007-05-10:2007/05/10/may-2007-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday May 10, 2007 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                  &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>April 2007 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2007/04/12/april-2007-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-04-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2007-04-12:2007/04/12/april-2007-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Short presentation on Port Knocking and Wake-On-LAN.                           &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday April 12, 2007 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>March 2007 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2007/03/08/march-2007-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-03-08T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2007-03-08:2007/03/08/march-2007-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday March 8, 2007 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                 &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>February 2007 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2007/02/08/february-2007-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-02-08T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2007-02-08:2007/02/08/february-2007-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At this month's meeting, the group will discuss what to have on display at the 
Southern California Linux Expo (SCALE) this weekend at the Los Angeles Airport 
Westin.                                                                        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday February 8, 2007 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>January 2007 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2007/01/11/january-2007-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-01-11T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2007-01-11:2007/01/11/january-2007-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Kerry Garrison, Senior Product Manager for Trixbox, will be on hand to       &lt;br /&gt;
demostrate installing and setting up a complete PBX system with their new    &lt;br /&gt;
Trixbox 2.0 package. Trixbox 2.0 makes it fast and simple to get an enterprise 
class PBX system up and running.                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday January 11, 2007 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>December 2006 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2006/12/14/december-2006-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-12-14T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2006-12-14:2006/12/14/december-2006-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Why Linux needs to be more like Windows -or- Impediments to enterprise Linux &lt;br /&gt;
adoption                                                                       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our speaker is Steve Friedl, a software consultant in Orange County who's been 
using UNIX since the early '80s, using Windows since the late '80s, and has  &lt;br /&gt;
more than 20 years of cross-platform consulting and commercial software      &lt;br /&gt;
development experience. He has taught advanced C/UNIX at Bell Labs, and is the 
only Microsoft MVP with "unix" in his domain name (unixwiz.net).               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He'll be making the case that Linux has some stumbling blocks that make      &lt;br /&gt;
enterprise management and deployment much more difficult than they need to be, 
and what road there might be to make some progress on these fronts.            &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday December 14, 2006 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                             &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>November 2006 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2006/11/09/november-2006-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-11-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2006-11-09:2006/11/09/november-2006-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monitoring the Local Weather with Linux                                        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of websites that will give you a weather report for your    &lt;br /&gt;
city, but what about your neighborhood? Ever wonder how hot your attic got   &lt;br /&gt;
during the summer or how well your air conditioner is working? Claude        &lt;br /&gt;
Felizardo will describe his 1-wire weather station and how it has grown from a 
simple kit with a single temperature sensor, wind speed, and direction to    &lt;br /&gt;
multiple sensors located throughout his house and publishes the measurements &lt;br /&gt;
to the Internet.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the Presenter:                                                           &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Claude has over 15 years experience developing software on Unix platforms and&lt;br /&gt;
has been playing with Linux since the late 90's. His friends and family think&lt;br /&gt;
he has too many gadgets, but he's always looking for something new to play   &lt;br /&gt;
with, especially if it works with Linux.                                       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday November 9, 2006 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>October 2006 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2006/10/12/october-2006-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-10-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2006-10-12:2006/10/12/october-2006-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;MySQL replication. MySQL Replication is the means by which one or more MySQL &lt;br /&gt;
databases can keep data synchronized with a master server. The scope of      &lt;br /&gt;
replicated data can cover any range, whether a single table, or              &lt;br /&gt;
indiscriminately all the databases on the master server. MySQL Replication is&lt;br /&gt;
beginning to find progressively more exposure in corporate production        &lt;br /&gt;
environments, where it sees use from providing hot backups, to distributing  &lt;br /&gt;
access load amongst large numbers of users. Solomon Chang will cover four main 
topics:                                                                      &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt; Requirements of MySQL Replication                                        &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt; Concepts of MySQL Replication                                            &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt; Configuring MySQL Replication                                            &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt; Troubleshooting MySQL Replication                                          &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soloman will provide a master to replicate from, so attendees are encouraged &lt;br /&gt;
to bring their own computers running MySQL (4.1 or later, please) to configure 
as a hands-on slave. Attendees will also have full access to Solomon's master. 
If there is time, more advanced topics will be discussed:                    &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt; Pyramid Architectures                                                    &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt; Dual Masters                                                             &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt; Circular Replication                                                     &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt; Circular Replication of Masters                                            &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the Speaker.                                                             &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solomon Chang, a MySQL-certified DBA, practices his skills at PriceGrabber.com 
and has been involved with LAMPsig since its inception in 2003. He is also   &lt;br /&gt;
currently co-authoring the MySQL Cluster Certification Guide by MySQL Press.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday October 12, 2006 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>September 2006 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2006/09/14/september-2006-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-09-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2006-09-14:2006/09/14/september-2006-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Open Forum.                                                                    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex Rosten will talk about some of his Linux projects.                        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday September 14, 2006 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                            &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>August 2006 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2006/08/10/august-2006-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-08-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2006-08-10:2006/08/10/august-2006-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday August 10, 2006 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                               &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>July 2006 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2006/07/13/july-2006-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-07-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2006-07-13:2006/07/13/july-2006-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monthly meeting.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Smith will, for the third time, attempt to present a "slice of life at &lt;br /&gt;
Yahoo!" -- an insiders guide to the fun and frivolity that goes on at one of &lt;br /&gt;
the world's largest content providers on the Internet.                         &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday July 13, 2006 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                 &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>June 2006 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2006/06/08/june-2006-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-06-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2006-06-08:2006/06/08/june-2006-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A couple of "Core OS" developers from Linspire will be our guest speakers, and 
they'll talk about the interesting languages and technologies they use in    &lt;br /&gt;
their distribution. When asked what they will present in detail, Clifford    &lt;br /&gt;
responded, "The core OS group at Linspire recently announced that we are     &lt;br /&gt;
standardizing on Haskell as our primary development language, whenever       &lt;br /&gt;
appropriate. In reality, we have been using both O'Caml and Haskell for years. 
Projects include:                                                            &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt; hardware detection and configuration,                                    &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt; creation of installation CDs,                                            &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt; package dependancy checker,                                              &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt; translation utilities for IRMA, and                                      &lt;br /&gt;
* many internal CGI/Web applications.                                        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"In the whirlwind of diversity that characterizes the Open Source development&lt;br /&gt;
model, functional programming provides us an eye of tranquility. In          &lt;br /&gt;
particular, static typing has proven invaluable. We will discuss the benefits&lt;br /&gt;
of systems programming with functional languages using the management of a   &lt;br /&gt;
Linux distribution as an example."                                             &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday June 8, 2006 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                  &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>May 2006 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2006/05/11/may-2006-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-05-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2006-05-11:2006/05/11/may-2006-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The topic for the evening will be "Getting a job in 2006: Is it the dot-com  &lt;br /&gt;
bubble all over again?" This event will include a presentation on the current&lt;br /&gt;
state of the job market in Los Angeles, with special emphasis on tech roles  &lt;br /&gt;
and open-source fields. There will also be a primer on how to prepare yourself 
to land the best job possible. Whether you are a linux guru or a newbie, this&lt;br /&gt;
session will provide valuable information on how to land a great job. A major&lt;br /&gt;
theme will be how to think like a corporate recruiter.                         &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the presenter:                                                         &lt;br /&gt;
For over 5 years, Todd Cranston-Cuebas has led technology hiring at          &lt;br /&gt;
Ticketmaster. He specializes in working with candidates who have backgrounds &lt;br /&gt;
in open-source tools and technologies. He has spoken at BOF sessions at a    &lt;br /&gt;
number of large technology conferences, including ApacheCon, OSCON, USENIX,  &lt;br /&gt;
and, of course, at SGVLUG meetings. He also is the scheduler and host for this 
year's monthly perl-centric "Tech Talks" for the LA.pm.                        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday May 11, 2006 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                  &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>April 2006 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2006/04/13/april-2006-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-04-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2006-04-13:2006/04/13/april-2006-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;PGP is an amazing tool for verification and encryption. However, many people &lt;br /&gt;
don't fully understand it-even people who use it. This talk mostly will cover&lt;br /&gt;
uses and effects of PGP. The discussion will focus on PGP and e-mail, and    &lt;br /&gt;
other topics will be covered as well. How cryptography works and the math    &lt;br /&gt;
behind it will not be covered.                                                 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keysigning party                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the key features of PGP is the "web of trust" that grows out of       &lt;br /&gt;
individuals signing each other's keys as a way of validating that the        &lt;br /&gt;
keyholder is indeed the "owner" of the key. We encourge you to create a key  &lt;br /&gt;
(if you don't already have one), post it to a public keyserver, and bring your 
"fingerprint" to the meeting for a keysigning party.                           &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the presenter                                                            &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phil Dibowitz is a UNIX systems administrator for the web systems team at    &lt;br /&gt;
Ticketmaster. The web systems team manages the Ticketmaster.com              &lt;br /&gt;
infrastructure: roughly 1500 Linux systems organized in four independent,    &lt;br /&gt;
redundant, and geographically seperate clusters across the United States. Phil 
has worked as a Linux, Solaris, and Network Administrator, and has a BS in   &lt;br /&gt;
Computer Engineering and Computer Science from USC. He is also the author of &lt;br /&gt;
iptstate(1), co-founder of the MSS Initiative, and works on IP Filter and the&lt;br /&gt;
USB Storage driver in theLlinux kernel. Find out more about Phil Dibowitz at &lt;br /&gt;
http://www.phildev.net/.                                                       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday April 13, 2006 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>March 2006 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2006/03/09/march-2006-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-03-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2006-03-09:2006/03/09/march-2006-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monthly meeting.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to a scheduling conflict, Chris was unable to present this last November,&lt;br /&gt;
so we've asked him to return this month.                                       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Smith of Yahoo! to present a slice of life-on-the-inside of the world's&lt;br /&gt;
largest content provider.                                                      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris will demonstrate some of the cutting edge work being conducted at Yahoo! 
Research Labs, all of which is powered by UNIX and open source computing.      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A member of Yahoo!'s Research Technology team, Chris has more than 10 years of 
experience developing enterprise software solutions for both Internet        &lt;br /&gt;
start-ups and as a Senior Java Architect for Sun Microsystems.                 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday March 9, 2006 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                 &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>February 2006 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2006/02/09/february-2006-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-02-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2006-02-09:2006/02/09/february-2006-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monthly meeting.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you mention "running more than one operating system" on a computer, most&lt;br /&gt;
people will think "dual boot", and for a wide variety of tasks that is quite &lt;br /&gt;
appropriate. But how many of you have thought of running more than one system&lt;br /&gt;
at the same time? Sure, you're only "one person," so why should the computer &lt;br /&gt;
act like you were two people doing different things?                           &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, you might not want to reboot your machine -- especially if you have a  &lt;br /&gt;
long-running task going on such as "seti at home" (since rebooting will cause&lt;br /&gt;
the "work unit" to be lost.) You might be a developer, and you're working on &lt;br /&gt;
something intended to be "cross platform" -- if every "rebuild-and-test" cycle 
included "reboot the machine", you'd tire of it rather quickly. Or perhaps you 
have two programs, each of which runs under a different OS, but you need to  &lt;br /&gt;
refer to the output of one program while working on the other.                 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this describes you and you haven't heard of VMware, then you need to attend 
the February SGVLUG meeting. This month we'll have Phil Anthony, a Sr. Systems 
Engineer from VMware, here to talk about what VMware has to offer -- he plans&lt;br /&gt;
to talk about the entier line -- from the ESX server to the workstation to   &lt;br /&gt;
their newest offering, the "free" VMware player. (this is "free as in beer", &lt;br /&gt;
folks...)                                                                      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday February 9, 2006 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>January 2006 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2006/01/12/january-2006-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-01-12T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2006-01-12:2006/01/12/january-2006-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monthly meeting.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles Finley of Transformix will be here to show off the Eclipse IDE by IBM. 
By popular vote, the presentation will be targeting the beginner, but there  &lt;br /&gt;
will be plenty of opportunity to dig into deeper subjects.                     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Finley has extensive software development and consulting experience on the 
HP 3000, as well as on a variety of large-scale computers, minicomputers, and&lt;br /&gt;
personal computers. He has over 30 years of combined experience in the data  &lt;br /&gt;
processing industry and has held both technical and management positions. He &lt;br /&gt;
has conducted over 70 computer-related seminars throughout the U.S. and Canada 
and is a former faculty member of the Industrial Relations Center at the     &lt;br /&gt;
California Institute of Technology (Cal Tech) in Pasadena. He studied        &lt;br /&gt;
management at UCLA, received a Certificate in Data Processing (CDP) from the &lt;br /&gt;
Data Processing Management Association, and holds a B.A. in business economics 
from the University of California, Santa Barbara.                              &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday January 12, 2006 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>December 2005 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2005/12/08/december-2005-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-12-08T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2005-12-08:2005/12/08/december-2005-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monthly meeting.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CinePaint is an open source software application primarily used for motion   &lt;br /&gt;
picture frame-by-frame retouching and dust-busting. Many films, such as Harry&lt;br /&gt;
Potter and Spider-Man, use CinePaint. It was used by Flash Film Works to add &lt;br /&gt;
flying arrows in The Last Samurai, work that helped them win a VES award for &lt;br /&gt;
Best Supporting Effects. CinePaint is the most popular open source application 
in motion picture production.                                                  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CinePaint project leader Robin Rowe will talk about the new Glasgow          &lt;br /&gt;
architecture, what's implemented, and what remains to be done. CinePaint     &lt;br /&gt;
Glasgow is scheduled for release on December 31, 2005. Glasgow runs on Linux,&lt;br /&gt;
Windows, and Mac OSX. Robin Rowe has led CinePaint since 2002. He's the      &lt;br /&gt;
founder of LinuxMovies.org. He's a partner in motion picture technology      &lt;br /&gt;
company MovieEditor.com.                                                       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://linuxmovies.movieeditor.com/                                            &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://sgvlug.org/index.php?option=com_content&amp;amp;task=view&amp;amp;id=17&amp;amp;Itemid=27.  &lt;br /&gt;
Date: Thursday December 8, 2005 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>November 2005 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2005/11/10/november-2005-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-11-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2005-11-10:2005/11/10/november-2005-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monthly meeting.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Smith of Yahoo! to present a slice of life-on-the-inside of the world's&lt;br /&gt;
largest [1] content provider.                                                  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris will demonstrate some of the cutting edge work being conducted at Yahoo! 
Research Labs, all of which is powered by UNIX and open source computing.      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A member of Yahoo!'s Research Technology team, Chris has more than 10 years of 
experience developing enterprise software solutions for both Internet        &lt;br /&gt;
start-ups and as a Senior Java Architect for Sun Microsystems.                 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dustin Laurence will also give a short "Cool Tools" talk on monitor          &lt;br /&gt;
adjustments at the start of the meeting.                                       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1]: if they're not, I'm sure Chris will correct us as appropriate.             &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday November 10, 2005 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                             &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>October 2005 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2005/10/13/october-2005-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-10-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2005-10-13:2005/10/13/october-2005-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;SGVLUG General Meeting                                                         &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topic: Elizabeth Fong from Three Rings will talk about Puzzle Pirates -- a   &lt;br /&gt;
cross-platform multiplayer RPG                                                 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yohoho! Puzzle Pirates (Y!PP) is a java-based persistant world RPG that has  &lt;br /&gt;
been quietly gaining accolades for the past three years. Come join us for our&lt;br /&gt;
October meeting where intern/developer Elizabeth Fong will tell tall (and not&lt;br /&gt;
so tall) tales about life in the game industry and how it relates to Linux.    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the presenter: Elizabeth has been programming for nearly 10 years and  &lt;br /&gt;
started with linux four years ago when she began hosting sites from her home &lt;br /&gt;
server. Starting this semester, she will be a freshman here at Caltech.        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://sgvlug.org/index.php?option=com_content&amp;amp;task=view&amp;amp;id=16&amp;amp;Itemid=27.  &lt;br /&gt;
Date: Thursday October 13, 2005 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                              &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>September 2005 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2005/09/08/september-2005-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-09-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2005-09-08:2005/09/08/september-2005-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Matt Ingenthron from Sun Microsystems will review Sun's involvement in the   &lt;br /&gt;
various open source communities and talk a bit about the latest, greatest hunk 
of intellectual property Sun's released to the wild: OpenSolaris.              &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt will discuss OpenSolaris's goals, how licensing works (and why you      &lt;br /&gt;
shouldn't be afraid of it) and how to get involved. This meeting will also   &lt;br /&gt;
cover what OpenSolaris is (and isn't) and have a brief demo. Take a look at  &lt;br /&gt;
http://www.opensolaris.org/os/about/ before attending to develop your own    &lt;br /&gt;
questions about the project.                                                   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt is a Technical Specialist for Sun Microsystems and supports a variety of&lt;br /&gt;
customers across the Western US. Based in Los Angeles, Matt has worked with a&lt;br /&gt;
number of customers on Linux and Solaris adoption and migration from other   &lt;br /&gt;
platforms. Matt is part of the Web Services practice of the Client Solutions &lt;br /&gt;
organization which specializes in use of Java Enterprise System software use &lt;br /&gt;
by customers on both platforms.                                                &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday September 8, 2005 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                             &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>August 2005 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2005/08/11/august-2005-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-08-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2005-08-11:2005/08/11/august-2005-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Orv Beach has been messing with computers for over 20 years. His first       &lt;br /&gt;
experience with computer operating systems was with CP/M, in the early '80s. &lt;br /&gt;
His first Linux was Slackware, in 1996. Since then he's moved to Red Hat Linux 
and then Fedora Core. While not a programmer, he's actively involved in the  &lt;br /&gt;
Linux community.                                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He's a principal member of the Simi-Conejo Linux Users Group, the Marketing  &lt;br /&gt;
chair for the Linux Expo of Southern California, and is currently employed as&lt;br /&gt;
the Information System Director at Simi Valley Hospital.                       &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Orv will demonstrate various command line commands and utilities that are    &lt;br /&gt;
useful for administering a Linux system. He'll throw in a few basic bash     &lt;br /&gt;
tricks as a bonus.                                                             &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday August 11, 2005 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                               &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>July 2005 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2005/07/14/july-2005-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-07-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2005-07-14:2005/07/14/july-2005-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;"Ubuntu: Linux from Outer Space," Jana Lingo.                                  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does an Internet pioneer and tycoon do when he still has too much money &lt;br /&gt;
after paying the Russians to take him to the International Space Station? If &lt;br /&gt;
you're Mark Shuttleworth, you start a Linux Company.                           &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jana Lingo will discuss the past, present, and future of one of the &lt;em&gt;hottest&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
current Linux distributions. Topics will include Ubuntu&lt;em&gt;s goals, philosophy, &lt;br /&gt;
history, and technology, as well as Jana&lt;/em&gt;s personal experiences with Ubuntu  &lt;br /&gt;
and its derivates.                                                             &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ms. Lingo has over 15 years of Information technology experience, both as a  &lt;br /&gt;
programmer and as a manager. She is currently working as a contract programmer 
for Unisys Corporation / Los Angeles County, in El Monte.                      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: New website is http://sgvlug.net                                         &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday July 14, 2005 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                 &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>June 2005 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2005/06/09/june-2005-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-06-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2005-06-09:2005/06/09/june-2005-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;"Linux and JPL's Mars Exploration Rover Project: Earth-based Planning,       &lt;br /&gt;
Simulation, and Really Remote Scheduling," Scott Maxwell and Frank Hartman,  &lt;br /&gt;
NASA JPL.                                                                      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA/JPL's Mars Exploration Rover project is the first time a JPL flight     &lt;br /&gt;
project has used Linux systems for critical mission operations. Scott Maxwell&lt;br /&gt;
and Frank Hartman, two of MER's rover drivers, also wrote the Rover Sequencing 
and Visualization Program (RSVP), the Linux-based software used on Earth to  &lt;br /&gt;
drive Spirit and Opportunity. Scott and Frank will discuss the software they &lt;br /&gt;
developed, as well as their experiences using Linux to drive two vehicles    &lt;br /&gt;
across the Martian terrain, a hundred million miles from Earth.                &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday June 9, 2005 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                  &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>May 2005 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2005/05/12/may-2005-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-05-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2005-05-12:2005/05/12/may-2005-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Please join us Thur at the sgvlug meeting (7-9pm at Caltech - please see     &lt;br /&gt;
www.sgvlug.org for directions)                                                 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giz (active member of lampsig.org) will present "A Whirlwind introduction to &lt;br /&gt;
PHP development basics and best practices."                                    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday May 12, 2005 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                  &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>April 2005 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2005/04/14/april-2005-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-04-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2005-04-14:2005/04/14/april-2005-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Adam Loughran from Novell/Suse will be presenting:                             &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Novell Linux Roadmap                                                           &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the completition of Novell's acquisition of Ximian and SuSE Linux, Novell 
now stands as a major advocate of Linux and of Open Source inititives. This  &lt;br /&gt;
month's San Gabriel Valley Linux Users Group meeting will host Adam Loughran,&lt;br /&gt;
Linux Corporate Strategist for Novell in So. California. Adam will be        &lt;br /&gt;
discussing Novell's recent moves into the Linux market including:              &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Novell's acquisition of Ximian and where XD2, Red Carpet, Evolution and Mono &lt;br /&gt;
fit into the Novell family of products and solutions Novell's recent releases&lt;br /&gt;
of Novell's Open Enterprise Server and what it means to the Linux community    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Novell's acquisition in SuSE Linux and what Novell is doing to accelerate the&lt;br /&gt;
adoption of Linux into the enterprise                                          &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A look at Novell Linux Desktop v9 and the latest news on Desktop Linux in the&lt;br /&gt;
enterprise.                                                                    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Novell's strategy in open source and how Novell will contribute to the       &lt;br /&gt;
community                                                                      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A discussion of other Novell products that leverage the most universal       &lt;br /&gt;
operating system on the market (Linux) including Identity Management, Resource 
Management and Web Services.                                                   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Novell will be providing a few give aways, so don't miss out on this         &lt;br /&gt;
opportunity to learn what Novell is doing to accelerate the adoption of Linux&lt;br /&gt;
and exchange ideas with those in the community.                                &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bio: Adam Loughran, Linux Strategist Novell inc                                &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday April 14, 2005 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>March 2005 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2005/03/10/march-2005-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-03-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2005-03-10:2005/03/10/march-2005-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;"Linux is the dominant OS for motion picture industry desktops and servers.  &lt;br /&gt;
Most of the blockbuster films in theaters today were produced using Linux. How 
did this happen? Why are all the large studios using Linux as their preferred&lt;br /&gt;
platform for creating feature animation and visual effects?"                   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robin Rowe is the founder of LinuxMovies.org, launched in 2002 for the       &lt;br /&gt;
advancement of Linux motion picture technology. He's the project leader for  &lt;br /&gt;
CinePaint, free open source software used to create visual effects in THE LAST 
SAMURAI and other feature films. He's a former Linux Journal columnist.        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday March 10, 2005 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                                &lt;br /&gt;
Location: Downs 107                                         &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>February 2005 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2005/02/10/february-2005-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-02-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2005-02-10:2005/02/10/february-2005-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mark Echeverri, who has years of experience in traditional software and      &lt;br /&gt;
systems engineering, says: "For the past couple of months, I've been working &lt;br /&gt;
with Plone. It's an impressive system, and not exactly something you pick up &lt;br /&gt;
in a Saturday. Previously, I had never done any Web-related development; Plone 
is a Zope tool that allows you to juggle Web portals like bowling            &lt;br /&gt;
pins...provided you know how to take advantage of it. Quite powerful."         &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About Zope and Plone:                                                          &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Zope is an open source application server for building content management   &lt;br /&gt;
systems, intranets, portals, and custom applications....Zope is written in   &lt;br /&gt;
Python, a highly-productive, object-oriented scripting language."              &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see http://www.zope.org/                                 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Plone is an out-of-the-box ready content management system that is built on &lt;br /&gt;
the powerful and free Zope Application server. It requires minimal effort to &lt;br /&gt;
set up, is deeply flexible, and provides you with a system for managing web  &lt;br /&gt;
content that is ideal for project groups, communities and intranets."          &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see http://plone.org/                                    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: Thursday February 10, 2005 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                             &lt;br /&gt;
Location: 117 Downs Laboratory                              &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>September 2003 Meeting</title><link href="http://www.sgvlug.org/2003/09/11/september-2003-meeting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-09-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>SGVLUG</name></author><id>tag:www.sgvlug.org,2003-09-11:2003/09/11/september-2003-meeting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At this month's meeting of the SGVLUG, Tim Frichtel will tell how his company&lt;br /&gt;
uses Postfix and Spamassassin to manage spam and provide reliable email for  &lt;br /&gt;
600 Lotus Notes users. Using low-cost Linux servers, this configuration stops&lt;br /&gt;
thousands of junk messages every day without downtime.                         &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8310                                                                       &lt;br /&gt;
Date: Thursday September 11, 2003 7:00 PM - 9:00 PM                            &lt;br /&gt;
Location: 101 Guggenheim Lab, Lees-Kubota Lecture Hall      &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>